(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T23:02:37.881593",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
こよりスケッチ
Koyori Sketch!
てんてー、はい
Teacher, yes!
はーい
Hi!
せーの、はい！
Ready, go! Yes!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
研究助手たち、全観測！
Research assistants, total observation!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
こよりの実験、観察
Koyori's experiment, observation!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
こよりの助手くん、わーねむ
Koyori's assistant, wow, so sleepy...
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
たいへんだー
Oh no!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うわぁ、エタノール
Whoa, ethanol!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
ずのーなのでね
Because I have a great brain!
みゃこ
Myako?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
マヨネーズは
Mayonnaise is...
お飲み物です
a drink!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
おっけー
Okay!
ごくごくごく
Gulp gulp gulp...
せーの
Ready, go!
ごくごくごく
Gulp gulp gulp...
やったー！
Yay!
まニアっかー
Maniacker!
マヨネーズは、お飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみに、ポテチは主食です
By the way, potato chips are my staple food!
はい、おにぃちゃん！
Yes, big brother!
全観測！
Total observation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always keep frozen udon in stock.
そうですか、はは！
Is that so? Haha!
やったー！
Yay!
証明完了、Q.E.D.！
Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
コポコポコポ
Glug glug glug...
実験開始！
Experiment start!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
のりのりはー
High spirits!
装備をのーる？
Equipping ethanol?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
大丈夫かな？
Is it going to be okay?
ういういういうい
Ui ui ui ui!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うわぁ、いきまっせー
Whoa, here I go!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
おもち、もちもち
Mochi, chewy mochi...
しょーがないね
Can't be helped, huh?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うふふ、ホロライブ
Ufufu, Hololive...
負けそう！
I'm gonna lose!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
わー、まいごー！
Wow, I'm lost!
おっけー
Okay!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うー、どっかーん！
Oooh, kaboom!
やったー！
Yay!
まニアっかー
Maniacker!
マヨネーズは、お飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみに、ポテチは主食です
By the way, potato chips are my staple food!
はい、おにぃちゃん！
Yes, big brother!
全観測！
Total observation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always keep frozen udon in stock.
そうですか、はは！
Is that so? Haha!
やったー！
Yay!
私の戦闘力は、54万です！
My battle power is 540,000!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
みゃこ
Myako?
私は、しゅーさいです
I am a genius!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
こよりの、おつみー、しょうちょうだよね
Koyori's Otsumi is iconic, right?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
たけのこ派ね！
I'm on Team Takenoko!
おっこー、いいー
Okko, good!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
あ！ 150、50！
Ah! 150, 50!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
シャンプーは、お飲み物ではありません！
Shampoo is not a drink!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
コポコポ、実験開始！
Glug glug, experiment start!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
しっぽも、ふりふり、ためです
Wagging my tail is a no-no!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
みんなの、応援が、いちばんだよ！
Everyone's support is the best!
右手ー！
Right hand!
やったー！
Yay!
まニアっかー
Maniacker!
マヨネーズは、お飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみに、ポテチは主食です
By the way, potato chips are my staple food!
はい、おにぃちゃん！
Yes, big brother!
全観測！
Total observation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always keep frozen udon in stock.
そうですか、はは！
Is that so? Haha!
やったー！
Yay!
せーの、ごくごくごく
Ready, go! Gulp gulp gulp...
こよは、こよりだよ
Koyo is Koyori!
せーの、ごくごくごく
Ready, go! Gulp gulp gulp...
はい、ハッシュタグ
Yes, hashtag!
こより実験中、でおねがいします
Please use #KoyoriLab!
おっけー！
Okay!
こよは、ずのーです
Koyo has a great brain!
ずのー、なのですか？
A great brain, is that so?
はい！やったー！
Yes! Yay!
こよりスケッチ
Koyori Sketch!
てんてー、はい
Teacher, yes!
はーい
Hi!
せーの、はい！
Ready, go! Yes!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
研究助手たち、全観測！
Research assistants, total observation!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
こよりの実験、観察
Koyori's experiment, observation!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
こよりの助手くん、わーねむ
Koyori's assistant, wow, so sleepy...
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
たいへんだー
Oh no!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うわぁ、エタノール
Whoa, ethanol!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
ずのーなのでね
Because I have a great brain!
みゃこ
Myako?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
マヨネーズは
Mayonnaise is...
お飲み物です
a drink!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
おっけー
Okay!
ごくごくごく
Gulp gulp gulp...
せーの
Ready, go!
ごくごくごく
Gulp gulp gulp...
やったー！
Yay!
まニアっかー
Maniacker!
マヨネーズは、お飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみに、ポテチは主食です
By the way, potato chips are my staple food!
はい、おにぃちゃん！
Yes, big brother!
全観測！
Total observation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always keep frozen udon in stock.
そうですか、はは！
Is that so? Haha!
やったー！
Yay!
証明完了、Q.E.D.！
Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
コポコポコポ
Glug glug glug...
実験開始！
Experiment start!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
のりのりはー
High spirits!
装備をのーる？
Equipping ethanol?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
大丈夫かな？
Is it going to be okay?
ういういういうい
Ui ui ui ui!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うわぁ、いきまっせー
Whoa, here I go!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
おもち、もちもち
Mochi, chewy mochi...
しょーがないね
Can't be helped, huh?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うふふ、ホロライブ
Ufufu, Hololive...
負けそう！
I'm gonna lose!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
わー、まいごー！
Wow, I'm lost!
おっけー
Okay!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
うー、どっかーん！
Oooh, kaboom!
やったー！
Yay!
まニアっかー
Maniacker!
マヨネーズは、お飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみに、ポテチは主食です
By the way, potato chips are my staple food!
はい、おにぃちゃん！
Yes, big brother!
全観測！
Total observation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always keep frozen udon in stock.
そうですか、はは！
Is that so? Haha!
やったー！
Yay!
私の戦闘力は、54万です！
My battle power is 540,000!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
みゃこ
Myako?
私は、しゅーさいです
I am a genius!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
こよりの、おつみー、しょうちょうだよね
Koyori's Otsumi is iconic, right?
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
たけのこ派ね！
I'm on Team Takenoko!
おっこー、いいー
Okko, good!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
あ！ 150、50！
Ah! 150, 50!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
シャンプーは、お飲み物ではありません！
Shampoo is not a drink!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
コポコポ、実験開始！
Glug glug, experiment start!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
しっぽも、ふりふり、ためです
Wagging my tail is a no-no!
はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
みんなの、応援が、いちばんだよ！
Everyone's support is the best!
右手ー！
Right hand!
やったー！
Yay!
まニアっかー
Maniacker!
マヨネーズは、お飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみに、ポテチは主食です
By the way, potato chips are my staple food!
はい、おにぃちゃん！
Yes, big brother!
はい、こんこよー！
Yes! Konkoyo!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、どうですか？
I always keep frozen udon in stock. How about you?
やったー！
Yay!
頭脳の！カッココヨー！
Brainy! Smart Koyori!
こんこよー、こよりだよー！
Konkoyo! It's Koyori!
せーのっ、カッココヨーです！
Ready, set, smart Koyori!
はい！ハッシュタグ #こより実験中！
Yes! Hashtag #KoyoriExperimenting!
オッケー！
Okay!
こよ、ずのー、ずのー、どうですか？
Koyo, brain, brain, how about that?
やったー！こよりスケッチ！
Yay! Koyori sketch!
てれっ！
Ta-dah!
ほえ？せーのっ！
Huh? Ready, set...
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
研究所らしい、実験！
An experiment fitting for a lab!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
助手くんの実験！
The helper's experiment!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
こよりの助手くん、ワンチーム！
Koyori's helpers, one team!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ふあー！
Whoa!
セーフ！
Safe!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
女の子のガチトーク、第四回！
Girls' Serious Talk, Vol. 4!
いぇーい！やったー！四回だ！
Yay! Woohoo! Vol. 4!
四回！四回目です！
Four! It's the fourth time!
そして今回もなんと、ゲストがいます！やったー！
And this time, we actually have a guest! Yay!
やったー！お邪魔してます！
Yay! Thanks for having me!
いらっしゃい！いらっしゃいませー！
Welcome! Welcome!
本日はノエル先輩が遊びに来てくれました！よろしくお願いいたします！
Today, Noel-senpai is here to play! Please treat us well!
よろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Please treat me well! Thank you!
ほな、ちょっと自己紹介がてら、今日の意気込みなど聞いてみましょうか。ラミィちゃん？
Well, why don't we hear your self-introductions and enthusiasm for today? Lamy-chan?
はい！ホロライブ五期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
Yes! From Hololive Generation 5, with her liver as her face, I'm Yukihana Lamy!
今日もどんな相談が来ているのか、楽しみです！よろしくお願いします！
I'm excited to see what consultations we have today! Nice to meet you!
そして、すのすののずのーの方、博衣こよりだよー！
And the brainy one of Sunosuno, I'm Hakui Koyori!
毎回、どんどんマシュマロが増えている気がします！みんなが相談...
I feel like the marshmallows are increasing every time! Everyone's consultations...
嬉しいことだ！
That's a happy thing!
ね、本当に嬉しくて。あとはみんなが結構ね、恋愛してるんだなと
Right, it's really pleasing. And everyone's quite in love...
ほくほくしております。今日もよろしくお願いします！
It makes my heart feel all warm. Thank you again today!
そしてゲストのノエル先輩、どうですか？この番組？
And our guest Noel-senpai, what do you think of this show?
はい！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Nice to meet you!
皆さん、こんまっする！ホロライブ三期生の白銀ノエルです！いや、ずっとね、ちょっと興味があり...
Everyone, Kon-muscle! From Hololive Gen 3, I'm Shirogane Noel! Honestly, I've had an interest in this for a while...
なんだったら、こよちゃんとかに「あれってゲスト、どんな感じなの？」って、ちらちら...
In fact, I've been giving Koyori-chan side-eyes like, "How do guests get on that show?"
「いつでも空いてますよ」みたいなね。そういう感じで、ちょっとかまちょムーブをしたら...
Hinting like, "I'm always free, you know." Doing that kind of attention-seeking move...
なんと今回、お呼びいただきました！ありがとうございます！
And somehow I got invited this time! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! We're so glad! Thank you!
この番組、よく観てるんですけど、とっても人を選ぶと思っておりまして...
I watch this show often, but I've always thought it's very niche...
まあでも、もちろん存じ上げておりますので...
But of course, I already knew that...
この深い時間にやるのにね、ぴったりの番組になってるので
It's the perfect deep-night show...
「行きたい」って言ってもらえるのすごい嬉しかったんです。今日はよろしくお願いします！
So I was really happy that you said you wanted to come. Nice to have you today!
お願いします！
Nice to be here!
NGはない感じですかね？
So there are no NG topics?
いやもう、もちろんNGなんてありません！
Of course not! There's no such thing as an NG topic!
本当ですか？本当にないの？
Really? There's absolutely none?
ない！
None!
いや、まあ、ちょっと皆さんの恋愛がどんな感じなのかっていうのも、それ次第なところはあるけど...
Well, how your love life is might depend on things, but...
団長的には、NGないかなって思ってます！
For me, I don't think there's any NG!
おー！さすが！この番組、団長もちょっと観させていただいておりまして、
Oh! As expected! I've been watching this show a bit too, Noel-senpai...
ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Thank you! We're so happy!
団長だったら、こんな気持ちだなとか、そういうのを想像しながらやってたので、今のところNGは...
I was imagining how I would feel if I were in those situations. So for now, my NG topics are...
ない！
None!
今のところ！今のところね！
For now! Just for now!
今日ちょっとぶっ飛んでたら、ちょっと分かんないかも！
If things get too crazy today, I might not know!
でも今日も同じくらいな感じかなと思いますので、はい！よろしくお願いします！
But I think today will be about the same level, so yes! Let's get started!
答えづらい時は答えづらいってはっきり言ってくださいね！
If a question is hard to answer, feel free to say it clearly!
了解しました！無理強いはいたしません！それでは見ていきましょう。一こ目！
Understood! We won't force you. Let's look at the first one!
ジャブで、これいっていいですか？
Can we start with this one as a jab?
ジャブ？
A jab?
「こよちゃんは「ノエル先輩」呼びですが、団長はもっと打ち解けて愛称呼びしてほしいなーって。「マリリン」並みの愛称考えちゃいませんか？」
"Koyo-chan calls you 'Noel-senpai,' but Noel, do you want her to be closer and call you by a nickname? Why not think of one on par with 'Marilyn'?"
あ、いいじゃないですか。さっきの配信でも言ってくれていたのか、というメッセージが。
Oh, that sounds great. Is this because of what was said in the previous stream?
そうなんだよね。
That's right.
なんか、こよちゃんね、ずっと団長のこと「ノエル先輩」って呼んでくれてて、
Koyo-chan has always called me "Noel-senpai," right?
ちょっとそろそろね、先輩呼びじゃなくて、打ち解けたいなって。
And I thought it's about time we move past "Senpai" and get closer.
え、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm glad!
色々遊んでるし、なんか呼び始めたら呼べそうな気がする。
We hang out a lot, so I feel like once I start, I can do it.
そう、呼び始めちゃえばね。慣れなんだよな、時間というよりは慣れ。
Exactly, once you start. It's about getting used to it, more than time.
ぜひ、呼びたい！なんだろうな？「ラミタン・ノエタン」的な？
I'd love to call you something! What should it be? Like "Lamitan/Noetan"?
「ラミタン・ノエタン」？
"Lamitan/Noetan"?
ノエタン？ノエ、ノエ...
Noetan? Noe, Noe...
ノエるん？ノエたん？
Noelun? Noetan?
ノエたん？ノエたん？
Noetan? Noetan?
ああ、ノエ…、ノエたん？
Ah, Noe... Noe-tan?
呼びやす。
Easy to say.
ラミちゃんもノエたんだよね？
Lamy calls you Noe-tan too, right?
あれ？ノエたんだよね？
Wait, it's Noe-tan, right?
あ、ノエたんか！
Ah, Noe-tan!
ノエたんだね。
Noe-tan it is.
イントネーション…
The intonation...
ノエたん、ノエって。じゃ、これは「ノエたん」で。
Noe-tan, Noe... Okay, "Noe-tan" it is.
行こうかね。
Let's go with that.
あ、下がる方。下がる方。
Ah, the falling tone. Falling tone.
ちょっとやっていきたいと思います、今日。
Let's get into today's topic.
やった！
Yay!
いいですね。
Sounds good.
さらに、ちょっと打ち解けられそうになったところで。
Now that we've gotten a bit closer...
これ、これが本当のジャブですね。
This is where the real jab comes in.
ええ、こちら。
Here we go.
お、来た。
Oh, here it is.
「男一人で『ちいかわ』の映画を観に行っても大丈夫でしょうか？」
"Is it okay for a guy to go see the Chiikawa movie alone?"
「周りから白い目で見られたりしないでしょうか？少し不安です。」
"Will people give me cold looks? I'm a bit worried."
「but this middle-aged guy wants to see Siren-chan and Shima-jiro too!」というのが来てますけど、どうですか？
"But this middle-aged guy wants to see Siren-chan and Shima-jiro too!" we received. What do you think?
あたり。
Of course!
え、何？ダメな理由ある？逆に。
Wait, why not? Is there any reason?
ないない、むしろいいよね。
Not at all! Actually, it's great!
だよね、いいじゃん、かわいい。
Right? It's fine, it's cute.
そうそう、これ結構配信でもすでに言ってるんですけど、それでも悩み多きリスナーさんがいたので。
Yeah, we've mentioned this on stream before, but we still have troubled listeners like this.
何も恥ずかしくない。
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
Not at all.
だって二人ともちいかわ映画観に行ってるもんね。
Because you two have also gone to see the Chiikawa movie, right?
うん、行ってる。いたよね、男一人の客。
Yeah, we have. There were guys by themselves, right?
もう、いた、いた、いた。しかもグッズもいっぱい着けてる。
Oh, absolutely! They even had lots of merch on!
分かる、分かる！
I know, right?
全然平気だよ。
It's totally fine.
「気にするな」というのをお伝えするために紹介しました。
We shared this just to tell you, "Don't worry about it!"
はい。
Yes.
しかも、あの、第5弾発表されたからね。
Plus, they just announced the fifth round of viewer gifts!
あ、そうだね。
Ah, that's right.
だから、目印アクセね。
So, the charm accessories.
より行ってほしい。
You should definitely go.
ねえ、ゲットしてきてほしいですよね、島二郎。
Yeah, I hope you get Shima-jiro.
島二郎をゲットしてください、ぜひ。
Please go get Shima-jiro, seriously.
はい、ぜひぜひ。
Yes, absolutely.
それでは、続いてこちらいきましょう。女の子からです。
Alright, let's move on to the next one. This is from a girl.
おお。
Oh.
「3人は学生時代スクールメイクなどしてましたか？」
"Did you three do school makeup back in your student days?"
「私もしたいのですが、よく分からないので参考にしたいです。」
"I want to do it too, but I don't really know how, so I'd like to use you as a reference."
「おすすめのコスメなどあれば聞きたい。」という、おすすめコスメはいくつか来てました、女子から。
"I'd like to know if you have any recommended cosmetics." We got a few requests about recommended cosmetics from girls.
おお、そうなんだ。
Oh, really?
ありがたいですね。
That's nice to hear.
してた？スクールメイク。
Did you do it? School makeup.
スクールメイク？
School makeup?
なんか薄メイクみたいな。ナチュラルメイク。
Like light makeup. Natural makeup.
どうなんだろ。学校行くときにメイク？なのか、あとは学生時代にメイクってしてた？
I wonder. Do they mean wearing makeup to school? Or just wearing makeup when you were a student?
してた。
I did.
してたわ。
I did too.
え、学校行くときもしてた？
Wait, even when going to school?
してた。
I did.
ええ！すごい！
Woah! Incredible!
してたけど…二人はしてなかった？
I did, but... didn't you two?
こよは学校行くときはしてなくて、お出かけのときちょっと見よう見まねでしてた。
Koyo didn't when going to school, but I tried mimicking it a bit when going out.
ああ、なるほど、なるほど。ノエたんは？
Ah, I see, I see. What about Noe-tan?
あ、ノエたんはね…
Ah, as for Noe-tan...
いや、でも、どうだろ。スクールメイク、学生時代から、高校とかってことだよね？
Hmm, I wonder. School makeup, since student days... they mean high school, right?
あ、そうそう。
Ah, yeah, yeah.
ええ、なんか興味はあったけど、してなかったかな。なんか厳しかった。
Well, I was interested, but I don't think I did it. My school was strict.
ああ、学校が？
Ah, the school was?
学校が厳しくて、なんかしてる子はいたの。
Yeah, school was strict. Some girls did it, though.
でも、すぐ怒られてて。
But they got scolded right away.
それを横目で見て「厳しいな、まだ早いか」と思って。
I watched that from the side and thought, "That's strict, maybe it's too early for me."
ああ、そんな感じだった。正しいと思うけどな。
Ah, I see. I think that's the right choice.
校則はそれぞれあるもんね。え、お出かけのときもしてなかった？
Well, every school has different rules. Wait, you didn't do it when going out either?
お出かけのときはね、ちょっと、見よう見まねでプチプラあるじゃん。
For going out, I tried mimicking it using drugstore makeup.
分かる！
I get it!
400円とか500円のクリームチークとか買って、チークだけ塗ってた黒歴史がある。
I have this dark history of buying a 400 or 500 yen cream blush and only applying blush.
え？チークだけ？
What? Only blush?
確かに、でも。
True, but...
やっぱさ、トータル大事じゃん。
The overall balance is important, after all.
そういうのを気にせず、口紅だけとかさ、チークだけっていう、なんか本当に下手くそだった思い出があるから。
Not caring about that and just wearing lipstick or blush... I just remember being really bad at it.
ちょっとね、そこは恥ずかしいなって感じだけど。
So looking back, it's a bit embarrassing.
チークオンリーはなかなか見んかもね。
"Blush only" is definitely a rare look.
そう、結構してた。ラミちゃんなんか、バッチリしてそう。
Yeah, I did it a lot. Lamy-chan seems like she'd do a perfect full face.
バッチリね。
Perfect, right?
ラミはしてたね。なんか、結構コスメ好きだったから。
I did. I really liked cosmetics.
別に誰に見られるわけでもなく、スクールメイクしてましたね。
Not that I had anyone to show it to, but I did wear school makeup.
ええ！なんか、コツというかさ、スクールだったからこそ、みたいなやり方とかあった？
Oh! Were there any tips or methods you used because it was for school?
学生時代。
Back in your student days.
ああ、傷跡、やっぱアイラインめっちゃ濃く引いちゃうとさ、バレちゃうじゃん。
Ah, but if you draw your eyeliner too thick, they'll find out.
ああ、確かに、バレないようにやってたんだ。ラミちゃんも。
一応ね。一応バレないようにというか
Ah, indeed. So you did it to avoid getting caught, Lamy-chan?
薄めに、薄めにやってた。
I kept it very light and subtle.
でも、なんか結構、眉とかも整えてたし。
But like, they groomed their eyebrows and stuff.
あ、たしかに。
Oh, that's true.
眉毛整え、
Grooming eyebrows...
眉ね。
Eyebrows, right?
大事。
It's important.
大事だよね。
It is important.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
そう。やっぱ眉毛はね、顔の印象だいぶ変わりますから。
Yeah, eyebrows really change the impression of your face.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
うん、だからだいぶナチュラルメイク。キャンメイクとかも使ってたよ。
Yeah, so it was pretty natural. They also used Canmake,
あの、プチプラの。
you know, that affordable brand.
いや、そう。キャンメイク。
Yeah, exactly. Canmake.
キャンメイクですよ、やっぱ。
Canmake is a must, after all.
神だよね。
It's a godsend.
神だね。
A godsend, indeed.
キャンメイク、今も使ってて、結構。
Actually, I still use Canmake quite a bit now.
うん、可愛いしね、パッケージ。
Yeah, the packaging is cute, too.
そう、可愛い、安い、しかも結構質が高い
Right, it's cute, cheap, and actually quite high quality,
と思っている。
in my opinion.
うん。
Yeah.
めっちゃいい。なんかその、この価格だけど、チークの塗りとかもすごい綺麗に出るし。
It's really good. Even at that price point, the blush goes on really beautifully.
うん。
Yeah.
そうそうそう。なんかね、コスメすごい好きなお友達がいるんですけど、
Yeah, yeah. I have a friend who's really into cosmetics,
その子もキャンメイク結構取り入れてて。
and she uses quite a bit of Canmake, too.
なんか、高いお金に固執しなくても、全然素敵なメイクできるなって。
It showed me you don't have to stick to expensive stuff to do great makeup.
おすすめしたかったです。
I wanted to recommend it.
おお、そうだね。
Oh, right.
おすすめだね。
Highly recommended.
ていうか、今ね、結構100均とかでもさ、
Actually, even at 100-yen shops nowadays,
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
メイクグッズって売ってるじゃないですか。
they sell makeup goods, right?
たしかに、ある。
True, they do.
あれも、なんか結構普通に使えるんよ。
Those are actually pretty usable, too.
え、そうなんだ！
Oh, really?
そうそうそうそう。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
よく使ったことなかった。おすすめとかある？
I haven't used them much. Any recommendations?
あ、でも、アイライナーとかは全然発色もいいし、落ちにくいし。
Ah, well, the eyeliners have great color payoff and don't smudge easily.
あ、そうんだ！すご。
Ah, really? Amazing.
そう。え、全然使えるよ。めっちゃいいよ。
Yeah, completely usable. They're really good.
なんか学生だとやっぱね、高いからね、メイク道具。
For students, makeup tools can be really expensive, after all.
そう、そう。
Yeah, yeah.
しかも、なんか、月一くらいの感じになるじゃん、一個ずつ。
And you only buy them like once a month, one by one.
うん。
Yeah.
とするとやっぱ100均、嬉しいよな。
So 100-yen shop makeup is a lifesaver.
100均、気軽に試せる。
With 100-yen shops, you can easily try things out.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
ぜひ参考にしてみてください。
Please use this as a reference!
はい。
Okay.
では、次、ちょっと男子からいきましょうかね。たぶん、男子。
Now, let's move on to a question from a guy. Probably a guy.
「美少女3人のフェチが知りたいです」
"I want to know the fetishes of the three beautiful girls."
うわあ、フェチ。
Whoa, fetish.
フェチ。
Fetish.
フェチか。何フェチ？
Fetish, huh? What kind of fetish?
ある？今、ちょっと考えてる。
Do you have one? I'm thinking about it now.
でもね、ラミ、結構ね、やっぱちょっと、汗の匂いかもしれないな。
Well, for me, it might actually be the smell of sweat.
匂い。
Smell.
そうんだ！言うてた、なんか。
Really? You mentioned something like that before.
そう、ちょっとやっぱ、みんなが、今さ、ちょっと露出が激しいじゃないですか、今。
Yeah, like when everyone's showing a bit of skin, like right now.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
やっぱでもなんか、ちょっと汗かいてそうなところの匂い嗅ぎたいもん。
I just want to sniff where they look like they might be sweating.
ええ！嗅がせたくない。
Wh-what?! I don't want you sniffing me!
正直。
Honestly.
いや、嗅がせたくないよ。
No, I really don't want you sniffing me.
汗は汗やで。
Sweat is just sweat, you know.
そうだ。
Right.
これ前にも、もしかしたら取り扱ったかもしれない。こよりは声。その時も言ってた気がしますね。
We might have talked about this before. For Koyori, it's voice. I think I said that then, too.
あ、声なんだ。
Ah, voice.
声。やっぱ、なんか、声優さんとか好きだったから、子供の頃から。
Voice. Since I've liked voice actors since I was a kid.
ああ、うん、うん。
Ah, yeah, yeah.
「あ、この人の声はこんな感じなんだな」みたいなのを、ちょっとまず気にしちゃうところありますね。
I tend to pay attention to things like, "Oh, so this is what their voice sounds like."
そう。ノエル先輩。
I see. What about Noel-senpai?
のえたんは？
What about Noetan?
のえた、のえ。のえたん。
Noeta... Noe... Noetan...
のえたん。
Noetan.
のえたんは、
As for Noetan...
さ、手かも。
maybe... hands.
おお、手。
Oh, hands.
手のどこ？どういう手が良いかというと？
Where on the hands? What kind of hands do you like?
え、むちむちな手が好き。むち、赤ちゃんみたいな。
Well, I like plump hands. Like baby hands.
え、そうなの？
Oh, really?
そう、赤ちゃんみたいな手が好き。
Yeah, hands that look like a baby's, I love them.
へえ。
Wow.
意外。
Unexpected.
意外。なんか、触ったら気持ちよさそうとか、そういう感じ？
Unexpected. Like, do they feel nice to touch, or something like that?
もそうだし、なんか、こう見た目的にも可愛いなと思って。
That, and they just look really cute, I think.
そう。で、なんかやっぱさ、手とかって、骨格とかなんかな。骨格でさ、
Right. And you know, hands show your skeletal structure. With bones,
見た目的には全然細いのに、なんか手だけさ、ちょっとむちむちしてる女の子とかおるじゃん。
even if they look slender overall, some girls have slightly plump hands, right?
たしかに、たしかに。
True, true.
そう。なんかそういうのに憧れるんだよね。団長、手、
Yeah. I really admire that. For me, my hands...
もうちょっと今画面にはね、映ってないけど、手、が、
they're not on screen right now, but my hands
結構やっぱり、なんか骨、骨がちょっとゴツゴツしてるんだよね。
are actually quite bony and rugged.
これがちょっとコンプレックスで。
I'm a bit self-conscious about that.
え、そうんだ。
Oh, really?
そう。なんか丸みがあるおててはずっと憧れてるの。
Yeah. I've always admired soft, rounded hands.
へえ、そうなんだ。
Wow, I see.
そう。だからクリームパンみたいな手とか、もう大好き。
Yeah. So I absolutely love hands that look like cream buns.
握りたくなるかもね。
You'd probably want to hold them.
そう。
Right.
なるほど。なんか今、でもコメント欄に「吉良吉影」って言われてて。
I see. Though someone in the comments just said "Yoshikage Kira"...
いやいや、そんな、あの、切ったり、そこまでだ。
No, no, I don't go cutting them off. That's going too far!
ホロライブのそこまでだ。
That's as far as Hololive goes.
そこまでだ。そこまで、怖い、怖い。
That's too far. Scary, scary.
ちょっと気にしちゃうな、というところですかね。
So it's just something you find yourself paying attention to, right?
そうですね、もうフェチです。
Yes, it's my fetish.
なるほど。では、もう一個ちょっと、はい。
I see. Then, one more... yes.
ちょっと、ノエル先輩に聞きたい。これ我々前回話してるやつなんですけど、
I want to ask Noel-senpai. We talked about this last time, but...
のえたね。
Noeta, right?
のえたん、ありがとうございました。
Thank you, Noetan.
はい、こちらです。「相手に蛙化する瞬間だとしたら、どんな瞬間ですか？よろしくお願いします」とのこと。
Yes, here it is. "If there's a moment you experience the 'frog-fying' phenomenon (sudden turn-off), what would it be? Please tell us." That's what it says.
あー、聞きたいですね。
Ah, I'd like to hear that.
聞きたい、聞きたい。
I want to hear, I want to hear!
え、なんか蛙化っていうか、なんか、前回は、なんか100年の恋も冷めるみたいなのって何？みたいな話をしていて...
Well, rather than "frog-fying," last time we talked about "what cools down a hundred years of love"...
で、こよりはなんかその、あの店員さんとかに怒っちゃうとかがあると冷めるみたいな話してたよね？
And Koyori, you said you'd lose interest if they got angry at store staff, right?
あー、話してたね。うんうん。
Ah, we did talk about that! Yeah, yeah.
え、そ、それもちろん知っておりますよ。
Oh, of course I know about that!
あははは、見てくださってありがとうございます。
Hahaha! Thank you for watching!
なんかありますか？
Do you have anything?
えー、団長その配信を見ながら「自分だったら何だろう？」ってちょっと思ってたんだけど...
Well, while watching that stream, I was thinking, "What would it be for me?"...
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
えー、なんか...
Well, let's see...
嘘、嘘かな、嘘つかれた時とか。嘘もさ、いろんな嘘があるじゃんか、で、
Maybe lies? When someone lies to me. There are different kinds of lies, though.
あー、あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
なんかそういう、嘘でも、優しい嘘なら良いと思うんだけど、なんか見栄を張るような嘘だと冷めちゃうかも。
If it's a kind lie, I think it's fine, but if it's a lie to show off, I might lose interest.
あー！
Ah!
え、見栄を張るような嘘って、例えば？
Wait, like what kind of lie to show off?
「俺の年収5000億ある」とか？
"My annual income is 500 billion yen" or something?
あ、そっち！？それはギャグだから良いんだけど、
Oh, that!? That's just a joke, so it's fine...
あ、それ良いんだ？
Oh, that's fine?
5000億はね。すごいね。5000億はね。
Well, 500 billion yen is a joke. 500 billion is...
なんか、まあ、そう、なんかちょっとした見栄、なんか自分を良く見せようっていうのは、まあ背伸びしたぐらいだったら良いかもだけど、なんかちょっと嫌、嫌かもな。
Well, like some small show-off, trying to look better... if it's just stretching themselves a bit it might be fine, but maybe it's just a bit off-putting.
うん。
Yeah.
まあね、嘘で繕ってもね、みたいな感じだよね。
Yeah, like there's no point in covering things up with lies.
そう、団長はね、弱いところを見たい。なんかそうやって嘘をついてまで、なんか強く見せよう、強くいようみたいなのは、ちょっと嫌だなって。
Yeah, I want to see their weak side. Showing off and pretending to be strong even if they have to lie about it is kind of a turn-off.
あ、もっとね、弱いね、本当のところを見せてほしいんだね、団長はね。
I see, so you want them to show their weak, true side.
そう、団長ね、幼児化したおじさんが好きだからね。
Exactly, because Noel likes old men who act like toddlers.
すごいピンポイントだな。
That's incredibly specific!
そう、幼児化したおじさんが好きなの。幼児も好きだもんね、そう。
Yes, I like old men who act like toddlers. And you also like toddlers, right? Yes.
何、なんか、キャラクターでいう、幼児も好き？ちょっと待って！
Wait, you like actual toddlers too? Hold on!
しょっ、しょしょ、小学生。事案、事案！うっかりのノエルだと思ったんですけど...
That's an incident! I thought you meant characters, but...
まあ、まあ、まあ、なんか、やっぱり、その、バキのね、バキっていう作品の、あのドリアンっていうキャラがいるんだけど、その人がね、そう、幼児化したおじいちゃん、そう、おじいちゃんなんだ。
Well, in Baki, there's a character named Dorian, and he's an old man who regresses to a toddler. He is an old man, though.
そう、それが本当にタイプで、
Yes, he is my absolute type.
ええ！？嘘ついてほしくないな、ありのままで。
What?! I don't want them to lie, just be as they are.
この人、幼児化するんだ。今ちょっと調べたんだけど、あ、調べた。そう、これ、幼児化する。キャンディ求めますから。
This guy actually regresses? I just looked him up. Yes, he regresses and begs for candy.
ムキむきのだ。僕をたくさん愛してって言ってる、キャンディが。
That buff guy? I see. "Love me a lot," he says, wanting candy.
そうなのよ。可愛いんだよ。
Yes. He's cute.
「キャンディ、キャンディ」ってすごいコメントで書かれてる。あ、そう、キャンディおじさんだからね。
The chat is full of "Candy, candy" comments. Yes, he's the candy old man.
で、「キャンディとかいらねえし」とか言わないでほしいっていうことですかね？
So you don't want him to say, "I don't need candy"?
そう、そう。強がんなくて、本当はキャンディが欲しいのに、「いやキャンディとか、そんな甘いもん食えねえし」とか、
Exactly. Trying to act tough like, "I can't eat sweet things like candy" even though he wants it.
言わないでいいからね、うん。ありのままでいようねって。
He doesn't need to say that. Just be as you are.
食べよう、食べようね。ありのままでいいよね。甘やかしてください。いや、わかるわ。強がりは嫌だ。のえたんに甘えられるのは最高やんけ。
Let's eat it. It's fine to be yourself. Please spoil him. I get it. Acting tough is a turn-off. Getting spoiled by Noel is the best anyway.
な、幼児化していいなら、すぐ、するけど、するけど、
If I can regress, I'll do it right away! I would, but...
いいんですか？しかもそれで愛してもらえるの、最高すぎる。
Is that allowed? And getting loved for it is just too amazing.
ね、最高すぎる。お世話したい、お世話。
Right? Too amazing. I want to take care of you, take care of you.
あ、じゃあ、ちょっと、これは幼児化に入るのかという質問なんですけど、はい。え、正直、下ネタ言う男子はモテませんか？という、
So, here's a question, and I wonder if this counts as toddler-like... "To be honest, are guys who tell dirty jokes unpopular?"
え、どのレベルの？
Wait, at what level?
え、わかんない。それはちょっと想像で、ここまでならオッケーとかあったら、ぜひそこも聞きたいんですけど。
I don't know. That's up to imagination. If there's a limit to what's okay, I'd like to hear that too.
下ネタ、下ネタ言う男子、
Dirty jokes... guys who tell dirty jokes...
下ネタによるくないかな。ねねぐらいのだったら全然気にしないけど。小学生男子みたいなの？そう、そう、そう。
Doesn't it depend on the dirty jokes? If it's on Nene's level, I wouldn't mind at all. Like elementary school boy jokes? Yeah, yeah.
良いかも。
That might be fine.
え、モテるかモテないかで考えると、どう思いますか？モテないんじゃない？
But thinking about whether they're popular or not, what do you think? Aren't they unpopular?
わかる。なんかデリカシーの問題じゃない？なんかその、女の子の前でさ、わざわざ下ネタを言わなくても良くないかってなる。
I think so. Isn't it a matter of delicacy? It's like, do they really need to say dirty jokes in front of girls?
そうよね。
That's true.
そう、そう。やっぱりそういう話っていうのはさ、関係値とかが大事で、そこまでの関係値に達しているってことは、下ネタ抜きでモテてる気がするから、
Right, right. Conversations like that require a certain level of closeness. If they've reached that level of closeness, they're probably already popular even without the dirty jokes.
下ネタでモテるってことは確かにないよね。確かに、それはないよね。ないか。ない、確かにない。
So dirty jokes themselves definitely don't make you popular. True, definitely not. There's no way.
なんか友達止まりになっちゃいそうな感じがする
I feel like we'd just end up as friends.
ああ、まあね。好きな男の子が下ネタめっちゃ言ってたら、でも、ちょっとやっぱ嫌だな。
Ah, well, yeah. If a guy I liked talked about dirty things a lot, I wouldn't like it.
ああ、確かに。
Ah, true.
ちょっと幻滅することもあるかも、下ネタの質によっては。 / 内容によってはね。
I might be a bit disillusioned, depending on the quality of the dirty joke. / Depending on the content.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
え、でも、この質問が来るってことは、言いながらモテたいってことなのかな？
Wait, but if we're getting this question, does it mean they want to say dirty jokes and still be popular?
どうなんだろう？ / 「俺は下ネタを言いたいんだ！」っていう...
How is it? / Like "I want to say dirty jokes!"
欲望。 / それでモテたら嬉しいなみたいな。
A desire. / And it'd be great if I could still be popular like that.
言っちゃうタイプだから、このまま生きててモテるなら、このままで生きるが、これでモテないならやめようかな、みたいな。
Like, "I'm the type who says them, so if I can be popular as I am, I'll keep doing it. But if not, maybe I should stop."
あるかもね。
That could be it.
いや、これ、ちょっとデカいぞ。この子が今後モテるかモテないか、ちょっと左右するかもしれない。
No, this is actually huge. This might decide whether this person becomes popular or not.
はっきり言っておかないと。「下ネタはたぶんモテないぞ！」
We need to be clear. "Dirty jokes probably won't make you popular!"
そうだね。モテる要素はないかもね。 / 確かに、確かに。
Right. There are no elements that make you popular in that. / True, true.
モテたいならちょっと控えたほうが。男子だけの元とかでね、言って、
If you want to be popular, you should hold back. Maybe just say them with other guys...
発散したりしたらいいんじゃないですかね？はい。
and let it out there, wouldn't that be fine? Yes.
うん。 / それができるのは君たち。
Yeah. / You guys are the ones who can do that.
ちょ、全然関係ない話していい？ / おお、いいよ。
Wait, can I talk about something completely unrelated? / Oh, sure.
あのさ、この間さ、友達とご飯に行ったんですよ。
Well, the other day, I went out for dinner with a friend.
そしたらそこの裏にいた、後ろにいた、男の子の4人組ぐらいがいたんですけど、
And then behind us, there was a group of about four guys...
えぐい下ネタ言ってて。
and they were saying some really gross dirty jokes.
もうずーっと、最初から最後まで下ネタ言ってて。
The entire time, from start to finish, they were talking dirty.
まじか。ま、でも、こっちまで聞こえちゃうのはあれだけど、でも友達同士で言ってるのは、ね。
I was like, wow. Well, it's a bit much that we could hear them, but they were just talking amongst friends.
まあ、飲み会の場とかはね。 / そうそう。
Well, at drinking parties and stuff. / Right, right.
男子ってやっぱりそういうもんなのかね？我々は男子じゃないじゃん。
Are guys really like that? We aren't guys, so we don't know.
男子だけの集まりを。
About all-guy gatherings.
みんな、そう、そうなの？みんなは。
Is everyone really like that?
そうなの。聞きたい。コメントのみんなにちょっと問いたい。 / でも、TPOをわきまえてくれって言ってる人もいるから。
Exactly. I want to ask. I want to ask everyone in the comments. / But some people are saying they should mind the time and place.
聞きないであげて。 / あ、声の大きさ大事ね。
Don't listen to them. / Ah, the volume is important.
聞こえてきちゃったんだもん、だって。
But it just drifted over to me.
それはね、そっちのボリュームの問題だからね。
True. That's a problem with their volume.
「人による」「言わないよ」あ、「学生はそうかも」
Some say, "It depends on the person," "I don't say them." Oh, "Maybe students do."
ああ、でも、そう、学生さんっぽかった。ちょっと。
Ah, but yeah, they did seem like students.
なるほどね。ちょっとまだ思春期なのかもしれないね。
I see. Maybe they're still in their puberty phase.
こより結構聞いちゃうかも。こういう話するんだって。
I actually end up listening. Like, "Oh, they talk about this kind of stuff."
気になっちゃうよね。こより女子校だったからさ、わからない本当に、学生の男の子たちが何を考えてるのか。
It piques my curiosity. I went to an all-girls school, so I really don't know what schoolboys are thinking.
新鮮だ。
It feels fresh.
ちなみにノエルたんは、あの、何校、共学、女子校どっちでしたっけ？
By the way, Noel-tan, which school was it? Co-ed or girls' school?
えっとね、高校まで共学で、大学で女子だった。
Let's see, co-ed up to high school, and then women's university.
おお、結構珍しいタイプ。じゃあ、どっちの目線も知ってるみたいな。
Oh, that's a rare pattern. So you know both perspectives.
そうだね。一応、回るけど、でも男子の話も気になるね。
Yeah. I can see both, but I'm still curious about what guys talk about.
聞きちゃいます。はい。じゃあ、そんな共学と、共学女子校と女子校な3人、それぞれがどうなのかという、
We end up listening. Yes. So, for the three of us from co-ed, co-ed/girls, and girls' schools, let's see how we differ.
こちら、3人に恋愛の2択についてお聞きしたいです。好きな人、恋愛対象に、刺激と安心どちらを求めますか？
This one: "I want to ask the three of us about a two-choice romance question. Between excitement and stability, which do you seek in a love interest?"
思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくれるほうか、一緒にいて落ち着く自然体でいられるほう、どちらを重視されますでしょうか？
Do you value someone who gets your heart racing with flirtatious words every time, or someone who lets you feel relaxed and natural when you're together?
私は安心タイプで、好きだよとかは伝えられるのですが、ドラマのようにドキッとさせるような言動は恥ずかしくてなかなかできません。
I'm the stability type, and while I can say "I love you," flirtatious actions like in dramas embarrass me too much.
女の子はどちらのほうが嬉しいですか？とのことなので、ちょっとこれ「せーの」で、刺激か安心かどちらか答えてみたいと思います。
Which one makes girls happier? So, on the count of three, let's answer: excitement or stability.
いいよ。 / はい。
Sounds good. / Okay.
せーの。 / 安心！
Ready, set... / Stability!
おお！ / 揃った！ / 揃ったね。
Oh! / We matched! / We did!
安心が。ここは揃いましたね。その心は？ラミたん。
Stability. We perfectly matched here. What's the reason? Lamy-tan.
ラミ？
Me?
刺激って、そのなんか今書いてあるのは、思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくるって書いてあるけど、
Excitement... according to what they wrote, is getting your heart racing with flirtatious words, right?
そんな思わせぶりな言動されたら、何？もう、困るんだけど。え、それ何？どういう意味？
But if someone flirts with me like that, it's just trouble. Like, "What? What does that mean?"
何、ラミのこと好きじゃないってこと？どういうこと？なんでそういうことすんの？
What, you don't actually like me? What is it? Why do that?
ってなっちゃうよ。 / そうだね、確かに。
I'd get so anxious. / True, indeed.
絶対安心のほうがいいな。
Stability is definitely better.
ノエルたんはどうですか？
How about you, Noel-tan?
いや、なんか、人生ってさ、生きるって大変やん。
Well, you know, life... just living is already hard enough.
それなのに刺激なんて、もういらんです。安心がほしい。やばい、優しさが。
On top of that, I don't need any more "excitement." I want stability. Man, I need kindness.
ほしい、やさしさ。 / ほしいでやんすよ。
We need kindness. / I really want it.
わかるわ、めちゃくちゃ。
I totally get it.
この恋愛というものを、その...
This thing called \"love\"...
ああ、なに、それは24時間一緒にいるってこと？どういうこと？
Ah, what? Does that mean being together 24 hours a day? What do you mean?
あ、っていうか、もう、なんだろう...
I mean, how should I put it...
付き合って、本当、行けるならゴールのその、結婚、そして生涯の最後、墓まで、みたいなぐらいのところを、
Dating and then, if possible, going all the way to the goal, marriage, and then to the very end of life, to the grave...
墓まで、みたいなことを考えて、恋愛というものを考えたときに、
Yeah, yeah, to the grave. When I think of love in that sense...
安心、がもう、大事すぎない？
...isn't \"peace of mind\" just way too important?
ずっと癒されて、安心、して、こう、なんか、ホッとする
I want a home where I can always be healed, feel safe, and be at ease.
家庭でありたい、と思うから、
That's what I want in a home, so...
そう、から、なんか、別に刺激いらんなぁってなる。
...yeah, so I feel like I don't really need any excitement.
まぁ、そうだね。長く一緒にいること考えたら、刺激って逆にちょっと困るかもな。
Well, that's true. If you think about being together for a long time, excitement might actually be a bit of a hassle.
しかもさ、刺激を求めるってことは、刺激ってさ、なんか慣れてくじゃん？
And also, seeking excitement... you eventually get used to excitement, right?
だから、この場合の刺激っていうのは、最終的にどこまで行くの？
So in this case, where does that excitement eventually lead?
確かに、ちょっと怖いね。
That is indeed a bit scary.
そう、長く見たときに、なんか、ちょっとした刺激じゃもう、もう、
Right, in the long run, a little excitement wouldn't even...
全然反応もしない、みたいになっちゃいそう。SMに発展していってしまうのか。
...register anymore, it seems. Will it develop into SM or something?
そっちに行く？まぁ、なんか刺激とかは最初の3回ぐらいまででいいんじゃないかな、みたいな感じよね。
Is that where it goes? Well, I feel like you only need excitement for maybe the first three times or so.
まあ、なんか付き合う前とかに、そういうドキドキ感があればいいんじゃない？
Yeah, as long as you have that kind of excitement before you start dating, it's fine, right?
勝手にドキドキするだろうしね。
You'll probably get excited on your own anyway.
はい、ということで、たぶん、わかんないですけど、多くの女の子は安心なんじゃないかなという。
Yes, so, although I don't know for sure, I think many girls prefer peace of mind...
はい。次、ちょっと恋愛とはまた別の話なんですけども。
Yes. Now, this is a slightly different topic from love.
脱毛しようか迷っています。カッコ、男子。
\"I'm wondering if I should get hair removal. (Male)\"
しろ！ / 早い、早い。
Do it! / That was fast!
女性から見て、毛があるのとないのとでは結構印象変わってくるのでしょうか？
\"From a woman's perspective, does having hair versus not having hair change the impression much?\"
え、しろ、なの？
Oh, is it \"do it\"?
え、もう絶対ひげ脱毛とかしたほうがよくない？だって、なんかさ、毎朝毎朝さ、剃ってるんでしょ？
Eh, isn't it absolutely better to get beard hair removal? Because, you know, they have to shave every single morning, right?
だって、それに、なんか刃がさ、やっぱ肌に当たると、刺激になってさ、そこが荒れちゃったりとかするわけじゃないですか。
And besides, when the razor touches the skin, it causes irritation, and that can cause breakouts, right?
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I see.
そういうの考えると、もう絶対ひげ脱毛なんて、ラミィが男性だったらまず真っ先にやる。
Considering all that, if I were a man, beard hair removal would absolutely be the very first thing I'd do.
まぁ確かに。
Well, certainly.
あの、ひげを生やしたい人は別にそのまま生やしてください、だけど、剃ってる人はね。
I mean, for those who want to grow a beard, by all means, go ahead, but for those who shave...
楽になると思うけど。
I think it would make life so much easier.
団長はそこまで、って感じ？
Danchou, you don't feel that strongly about it?
なんか、団長は、あんまり、その...ラミィはさ、その人のことを思って言ってくれてるじゃん。
Well, for me, I don't really... Lamy, you're saying that out of consideration for them, right?
「あ、そういう視点があるんだ」って思ったけど、団長はちょっとね、自分の好みで言うと、
I thought, \"Ah, that's a good perspective,\" but speaking from my own preference...
なんか、本当にどっちでもよくて。
...I really don't mind either way.
え、なんかさ、毛、毛があったときに、その、やっぱ毛ってさ、意味があるところに生えるわけじゃん。
Like, when there's hair, hair grows where there's a purpose, right?
毛深い人はその分、体をなんか守んなきゃいけないのかなと思って。
So I think, maybe hairy people need to protect their bodies more.
ストーリーがあるんだね。
There's a story behind it.
そう。ストーリー、なんか、なんかすごいクマさんみたいだな、と、いう感じで。
Yeah, like a story. I just feel like they're like a big, fluffy bear.
いや、でも、なんか本当にね、脱毛しようかしないで言うなら、脱毛しようか迷ってるんだったらしたほうがいいと思う。
But really, if we're talking about whether to do it or not, if you're already hesitant, I think you should do it.
そう、なんか、女子から見て、なんか毛があったほうがとかないほうがとかは、色々人それぞれだと思うけど、やっぱ自分自身だと思うな。
Yeah, from a girl's perspective, whether hair is better or not varies from person to person, but in the end, it's about yourself.
しかも、脱毛って痛い。 / そうだね。お金もかかりますし。
Plus, hair removal hurts. / True. And it costs money.
から、その、周りからどう見られるかよりも、自分自身がやって、なんかこう、過ごしやすいかでやったほうが後悔もないと思うので。
So instead of worrying about how others see you, you'll have fewer regrets if you decide based on what makes you feel comfortable.
確かに。それも。
Certainly. That too.
あれだよね、毛がある人を見て、毛があるな、嫌だなと思うことはないよね。
But, you know, when you see someone with body hair, you don't look at them and think, \"Oh, they have hair, how unpleasant,\" right?
そうだね、そんな毛深い人を見たことがないかも。
That's true. I don't think I've ever really seen an exceptionally hairy person.
そうそう、道行く人でしか見ないから、そこで考えること、そんなないけど。
Right, right. We only see random passersby on the street, so we don't really think about it that deeply.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
ということであんまり気にしたことないね。
So I haven't really minded it that much.
うん。
Yeah.
でもなんかヒゲを、そう脱毛したいと迷ってるならした方がいいって言うラミたんの熱い...
But Lamy-tan's passionate advice that if you're on the fence about beard hair removal, you should just do it...
熱い。
Passionate...
絶対！だって、困ってるそう、だもんね。きっと。そのやっぱ、毎回剃ったりとかね。
Absolutely! Because you must be having trouble with it, right? Like shaving every single time.
肌荒れしたりとか。
Or getting skin irritation.
圧倒的に自分がやっぱ脱毛して良かったと感じているから、っていうのもあるかな。
I think it's mostly because I personally feel so glad that I got it done.
あー、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
楽ちんだからなーってね。
Because it makes things so much easier.
うん。確かにね。楽ちんではあるな。
Yeah, definitely. It really does make it easy.
意外とね、そのすごい痛いとことか、麻酔とかやれるしね。わかんない、顔どうなんだろ？ヒゲってどうなんだろ？わかんないけど。
Actually, for the really painful parts, you can use anesthesia. I don't know about beards, though.
わかんないけど。
I don't know either.
ね。どうなんでしょうか。調べてみてもいいのではないかと思いおます。
Yeah. I wonder how it is. I think it might be worth looking into.
はい。
Yes.
さあ、では続きまして。ちょっと変なのいっていいですか？
Now then, moving on. Can I go with a slightly weird one?
お、いいよ。
Oh, go ahead!
夜も更けてまいりましたので、えー。
Since the night is getting late...
はい。
Yes.
お風呂で異性に洗わせてもいい場所の限界を教えてください、という。
"Please tell me the limit of where it's okay to let the opposite sex wash you in the bath."
何それ！？ええ！？
What is that?! What?!
限界？限界。
The limit? The limit.
誰、この異性って？
Who is this "opposite sex"?
そう、何なの？
Yeah, who is it?
そうなの。なんか、え、店？彼女？どっち？みたいな。
Exactly. It's like, "Wait, is it a parlor? Or a girlfriend? Which one?"
この、誰、誰なの？
Who is this person?
異性って、誰、誰なの？
Who is this "opposite sex"?
わかんないけど。
I have no idea.
でもこれは、彼女なのだとしたら、
But if it's a girlfriend,
彼女が洗いたいなら、どこまででもいいんじゃない？って思った。
and she wants to wash you, isn't anywhere okay? That's what I thought.
結果...どういうこと？その...
Wait... what does that mean? Like...
こよが彼女だったら、ラミはどこも洗ってもいいってこと？
If Koyo is the girlfriend, does that mean Lamy can wash her anywhere?
違う違う違う！え、何？ラミたんが洗ってくれるの？
No, no, no! What? Lamy-tan, you're going to wash me?
待って、話が変わってくるんですけど、そこは。
Wait, that completely changes the story.
そうだったら、っていうこと。
I meant, "if that were the case".
え、なんか、え、どっちだろう？えっと...
Um, wait, which way is it? Let's see...
こよが彼女で、
If Koyo is the girlfriend,
で、えっと、こよが...こよが彼女、ちょっと難しいな。
and, um... Koyo is the girlfriend... Wait, this is getting confusing.
彼女が、え、君の全部洗ってあげたいの、って言ってきて、
If your girlfriend says, "Hey, I want to wash all of you,"
自分も、まんざらでもないなら、
and you don't mind it either,
全部洗わせていいんじゃない？
then shouldn't you just let her wash everything?
おお...
Oh...
あの、マシュマロの人になりきってるのね、今。なりきった上で、あ、なるほど。
You're putting yourself in the shoes of the marshmallow sender right now. Oh, I see.
そうそうそう。なりきった上で、そういうこと、そうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Based on that perspective. Yes, exactly.
え、でも、でもこのマシュマロの人は、
But, but I think this marshmallow sender...
団長たちが、その、異性が洗うならどこまで許せる？って言われてるんだと、思って聞いてたから。
...was asking you girls where you would draw the line if the opposite sex washed you.
あ、じゃあ、洗ってほしいなって言う側、言われる側の、
Ah, so the side that wants to be washed, or the side being asked...
洗ってほしいな？
"Wants to be washed"?
で、この、子が、彼女に対して、洗ってほしいなって言いたいのかも、しれないな、かなと。
And maybe this person wants to tell their girlfriend that they want to be washed.
そしたら、どこまで求めていいですか？っていう、ことにするじゃん。
In that case, it becomes, "how far can I ask her to go?"
いや、難しい。
Man, this is so complicated.
自分の立ち位置がわからない、自分、自分。自分、誰？
I don't know what my stance is here! Who am I in this scenario?
この子の、この子の彼女だとして、この、おマシュマロ主の、
Let's say you are his girlfriend. This marshmallow sender's...
の、彼女だとして、で、このマシュマロ主である、この彼ぴくんが、
...girlfriend, and this marshmallow sender boyfriend...
一緒にお風呂に入ろう、ということになりました。
...says, "Let's take a bath together."
で、この彼ぴくんは、あの、洗ってほしいっぽい、自分の体を。
And this boyfriend seems to want his body washed.
あ、洗うこと、はい。
Ah, to wash him, yes.
そうそうそう、洗ってほしいっぽくて、ちょっと洗いっこしようよ、みたいな時に、
Exactly. He wants to be washed, so when he says, "Let's wash each other"...
どこまでだったらラインを越えないのか。
...how far can you go without crossing the line?
すごいね、もうライン超えてると思うんだけど。
That's crazy, I think he's already crossed the line!
超えてるか、うふふ。そっか。
He crossed it? I see.
もう、お風呂入ってるならもう...
I mean, if you're already in the bath together, then...
ない、そんな。
No way, there is no line left.
あ、そっか。えー。
Ah, is that so? Wow.
でもなんか、普通だったら背中までだよなって思ったりね。
But normally, you'd think it would stop at the back, right?
おお、なるほどね。
Oh, I see.
背中を流す？うん。背中の洗いっこ。までなのかな。
Washing their back? Yeah. Washing each other's backs.
いや、でも、ラミがこよの体洗ってもいいんだったら、どこまででも洗いますけど。
Though, if I'm allowed to wash Koyo's body, I'd wash her anywhere.
え、のいたんものいたんも、どこまででも洗うよ。
And Noitan too! Noitan, I'll wash you anywhere.
ほんまに？
Really?
洗うけど。
I'll wash you.
え、僕が男だったら、どこまででも洗ってくれるの？じゃあ。
Wait, if I were a guy, you'd wash me anywhere? Then...
お願いします。
Please do.
え、でもさ、ラミ、団長の体洗ってくれるって、
But wait, if Lamy washes Dancho's body...
言ったけど、団長、あれちょっとややこしいよ、体洗うルーティンが。
...I said I would, but Dancho, your body washing routine is a bit complicated.
ラミも多分美容にね、色々やってるから、細かく、細かいかも知らんけど。
Lamy, you probably do a lot for beauty too, so your routine might be quite detailed too.
あ、いいよ、覚える覚える。スクラブとか、
Oh, it's fine, I'll memorize it. Like scrubs and...
あ、全部覚える。まずは、泡立てるじゃん、
I'll learn it all. First, lather it up, right?
で、体は洗うけど、あの、大事あるじゃんね、その下の、大事なところは
Then, I'll wash the body, but you know, the sensitive parts, the important areas down there...
専用の石鹸で洗ってほしい。
I want you to wash those with specialized soap.
ラミィも別の石鹸で洗ってる。
Lamy washes with a different soap too.
そう、そうでしょ？
See, right?
そういうのをちゃんとやってくれるならいいよ。
If they do that properly, then it's fine.
あ、ラミィね。なるほどね。
Ah, Lamy. I see.
なるほど、なるほど。分かった、分かった。
I see, I see. I get it.
全部覚えるわ。1から10まで全部覚えるから、洗い流させてもらっていい？
I'll remember everything from 1 to 10, so can you let me wash you?
それは...それならいいかな。うん。
That... if that's the case, I guess it's fine. Yeah.
おっけおっけ、任せて。
Okay, okay. Leave it to me.
いい女すぎるでしょ。
You're way too good of a woman.
なんかこの番組やると、ラミィちゃんがいい女であることがどんどん世間にバレていく。
When we do this show, Lamy-chan's status as a "good woman" just keeps getting exposed to the public.
ありがたい、ありがたい。
I'm so grateful.
でもこよちゃんも言ってね。何がどうとか、全部覚えるんで。
But you tell me too, Koyori-chan. What and how you like things, because I'll remember it all.
こよはなんかあまり特にないから、ラミィちゃんがやってるやつをやってもらったほうが綺麗になりそう。
Koyo doesn't really have any specific preferences, so having you do it your way would probably make me cleaner.
あ、なるほど、なるほど、分かった。
Ah, I see, I see. Got it.
そのままお任せね。
I'll leave it to you then.
お任せします。任せて、任せて。
I'll leave it in your hands. Trust me, trust me.
でも今のので分かったのは、女の子の体を洗いたいんだったら、女の子は結構、その、いろいろ気にしてることあるから。
But what I understood from this is, if you want to wash a girl's body, girls have quite a lot of things they worry about.
そこを気遣ってあげるといいんじゃないかっていう感じですかね。
So it's probably best to be considerate of that.
そうだね。
That's true.
それができたら120点だね。120点ですね。
If you can do that, it's 120 points. 120 points indeed.
ちょっとね、面白かったんで、あの、ちょっとやっちゃいました、すいません。
It was a bit interesting, so I went ahead and did it, sorry.
え、じゃ、ちょっとノエたんから、だからこその恋愛相談モードに入りたいと思います。
Well, let's move into the love consultation mode specifically because of Noe-tan.
はい、恋愛相談1発目、ご紹介いたしましょう。
Yes, let's introduce our first love consultation.
「団長がいるからということで、ご相談させてください。」
"Since the leader (Danchou) is here, please let me consult with you."
「今、自分には、おっぺえの大きい彼女がいます。」
"Right now, I have a girlfriend with large breasts."
おおー！
Oh!
「そして何を隠そう、自分は、大のおっぺえ星人であります。」
"And to tell the truth, I am a huge breast-man (oppai seijin)."
おお。
Oh.
ウィンウィンじゃん。ウィンウィン。
It's a win-win. Win-win.
「ですが、彼女にはかっこいいところだけを見せたく、そのことについては言っておらず、」
"But, I only want to show my cool side to her, so I haven't told her about that,"
「『べ、別に興味ねえし』みたいな態度をとってしまいます。」
"and I end up taking an attitude like, 'I-It's not like I'm interested or anything.'"
あ、なんか、ちょっとさっきのツンデレに、ちょっと繋がる感じだけど。
Ah, that somehow connects a bit to the tsundere topic from earlier.
「このまま我慢してかっこいい自分を見せ続けるか、それとも引かれることを前提にありのまま自分をさらけ出すのがいいか、どっちがいいんでしょうか？おっぺえプルンプルン」だそうです。
"Should I keep enduring this and showing my cool self, or should I expose my true self, assuming I might get turned down? Which is better? Oppai Plun-Plun," they say.
これ、でも、ノエたん、決まってるでしょ、答え。
But for this, Noe-tan, the answer is already decided, right?
いや、決まってる、でも、
Yeah, it's decided. But...
ま、何ヶ月かとかね、そういうのも関係すると思うけど、でもさ、
Well, I think how many months they've been together also matters, but still...
やっぱ、さらけ出したほうがいい。
As expected, it's better to expose yourself.
だって、いつまでね、そのさ、かっこいい姿、
Because, how long can you keep up that cool facade?
いや、最初だけだよ、本当に。バレる。っていうか、なんならバレてると思う、もう。
No, that's really only at the beginning. She'll find out. Or rather, I think she already knows.
おっぱい星人だってことが。
That you're an oppai seijin.
「目線でバレるんじゃないか」ってコメントが。
There's a comment saying, "Won't she notice from your gaze?"
ああ。どうですか？なんか、隠しきることある？
Oh. What do you think? Is there any way to completely hide it?
いや、なんか団長、感じないけど、その、感じたらそう、街中とか。
Well, as for me (Danchou), I don't really notice, but if you notice it, like in town...
え、そうなんだ？
Eh, really?
本当に？え、なんか、あるよね。そのさ、結構、コメントとかでもさ、「え、そなり（？）大胸筋がデカいと目線とか気になりませんか？」みたいなさ。
Really? Eh, somehow, it happens, right? Even in the comments, they say, "Wait, aren't you concerned about people's gazes when you have large pecs (breasts)?"
気になったこと、ない。
I've never been concerned about it.
え！ない？え！ないの？
Eh! You're not? Eh! You aren't?
ない。絶対コンビニの店員さんとか見ちゃいそう。
Nope. I feel like convenience store clerks would definitely look.
いや、ない？ラミィですら毎回会ったら見てるよ。
No... No? Even Lamy looks every time we meet!
見ているの？それはそう、見ちゃう。
(Note: Subtitle matches what is heard in Japanese: "見てるの？" "それはそう、見ちゃう。")
You look? Well, yeah, I do look.
うん、うん。それ、気づいてないんか？
Yeah. Does she not notice that?
あんまり、もしかしたら、そういうの感じないような子だったら気づいてないかもしれんけど、
Maybe if she's the type of girl who doesn't really notice those things, she might not have realized it,
でもさ、ほら、ラミィとかね、こよちゃんも、あるからさ、
but you see, Lamy and Koyori-chan also have them, right?
感じたりする？街中で。
Do you feel it? In town.
街中... 街中はない。はない？
In town... Not in town. Not in town?
ではないけど、でも、ああ、今なんか、ちょっと目線下だな、って思うことは、
Not really, but, ah, there are times when I think, "His gaze is a bit low right now."
あるかな。
I guess.
対面向かってね、話すタイミングとかが、ある。
Like when speaking face-to-face, those moments happen.
そうだね。お店の人とかもね。
True. Like with store staff as well.
いや、え、でも、どう、どうだろう？なんか、こよ的には、
No, but how, how is it? For Koyori,
でも、ちょっと、おっぺえ星人までを、急に言って、なんか、
but, if you suddenly say you're an oppai seijin, somehow...
それで何かが起きてしまったらちょっと怖いなって、彼女の気持ちになると。
if something happens because of that, it's a bit scary, if I put myself in the girlfriend's shoes.
あ、そうだね。そうだね、なんかさ、いきなりはね。
Ah, indeed. True, somehow... doing it suddenly, you know?
いきなりだと、え、もしかして、おっぱいが大きいから付き合ったのかな、とか、
If you do it suddenly, like, "Wait, did you date me just because my breasts are big?" or something like that.
思われちゃうかも。思われちゃう。
She might think that. She will think that.
怖いかも。確かに。
That could be scary. True.
本当に付き合って、どれくらいの期間なのか、プラス、
It really depends on how long you've been dating, plus...
あとは、もうちょっと、徐々にだね。やっぱり徐々に、
after that, you should do it gradually. Yes, gradually,
っていう、なんか、褒める感じで。難しいよな。
by praising her. It's difficult.
いや、確かに、難しい。
No, indeed, it's difficult.
なんか一気に難しくなってきた。確かに。
Somehow it suddenly got really difficult. Indeed.
でも、かっこつけるのは、なんか、あれかな、続かないと思うんだよね。
But acting cool, I don't think that can last, you know?
そうだね。
True.
「べ、別に興味ねえし」は、嘘になっちゃってるからな。そう、嘘、嘘。そう、嘘になっちゃう。
Saying "I-It's not like I'm interested" is basically a lie. Yes, a lie, a lie. It becomes a lie.
もしそういう、その、言えるようなタイミングが来たときには、
If a timing comes when you can say it,
「君自身が好きなことは大前提に、おっぱいも大好きだよ」みたいな。
"with the premise that I like you yourself, I also love your breasts," or something like that.
言う、言うことないの？言うことないか。
(Note: Subtitle matches what is heard in Japanese: "言う、言うことないの？" "言うことないか。")
Saying... you don't say that? I guess not.
ま、でも、あれですね、別に好き、
Well, but, you see, you don't necessarily...
だからね、しーっていう態度はなしで
So maybe instead of shushing them,
普通に過ごせばいいのかもね。なんかその...
just act normal. Like...
わざわざ「おっぱい星人です」って制限することは
There's no need to limit yourself by saying, "I'm a boob monster."
しなくていいから。
You don't have to do that.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
なんかそう、なんかちょっと強がってるというか
Right, it's like they're trying to act tough,
クールぶってる？
or acting cool?
でも、団長だったら嬉しいけどね。ちなみに、あの...
But as for me, I'd actually be happy, to be honest.
「おっぱい星人」から。
Coming from a boob monster.
おっぱい星人、確かに。
Boob monster, indeed.
おっぱい星人を愛してる感じで。
Feeling loved by a boob monster.
嬉しい。
I'd be happy.
ラミィちゃんは？
What about you, Lamy?
ラミィも、立派な...
Lamy is also quite...
おっぱい星人？
Boob monster?
おっぱい星人、嬉しいよ。
I'd be happy to have boob monsters.
おっぱい星人だったら、全然、「ラミィの胸に飛んでおいで」ってなるから。
If they're boob monsters, I'd be like, "Come fly into Lamy's chest."
確かに。
True.
この胸でこう、繋ぎ止められるみたいなところもある？なんか。
Is there a sense of being able to tie them down with these boobs?
そういうのはないけど。
Not like that, but...
ないか、ないか。
Right, right.
おっぱい、その、今付き合ってるってことじゃん。
I mean, you're currently dating them.
付き合ってる上で、おっぱいまで好きなら、もう...
If they love your boobs on top of dating you...
あ、もうだって、魅力×2やん、みたいな。
It feels like attraction times two.
じゃあずっと、このまま好きでい続けてくれるな、みたいな安心感。
It gives a sense of security, like, "They'll keep loving me."
いや、ないか。
Or maybe not.
なんかさ、思うのが...
I was thinking...
なんかその、自分自身にとってのおっぱいは、そんなに価値は感じてなくて。
For me personally, I don't really find much value in boobs.
えー！
What?!
自分の？
Your own?
うん、そこ。
Yeah, that.
それ？それは...
Really? That is...
もったいない！
What a waste!
もったいないよ。
It's such a waste.
世間一般的に。
But I do understand that there are people out there who love them, generally speaking.
だから、ありがたいなみたいに思うけど、修飾する。
So I'm grateful for that, but...
それでなんか、繋ぎ止められるとか、強いだろみたいな自信には繋がらないかな。
it doesn't really translate to confidence like, "This will tie them down."
なるほどね。
I see.
そう。
Yeah.
ちょっと余裕がない女なのかもしれない。
Maybe you're a woman who lacks leeway.
自分の価値を見出したい、みたいな。自分に自信がないからなのかな。
Like wanting to find your own value. Maybe it's because of a lack of self-confidence.
ああ、そう、そういうところも、でもなんか可愛いけどね。
Ah, but even that part of you is cute.
可愛いよ。
It is cute.
失言って言われてるので。
People are calling it a slip of the tongue.
つなぎとめられるは失言だったみたいですね。
"Tying them down" seems to have been a slip of the tongue.
はい、では続いて、えーっと...これちょっと答えてあげたいなという。
Alright, next up... I'd like to answer this one.
「スノースノウのお二人、そしてゲストの団長、こんばんは。」
"Good evening to the two of Snow Snow, and the guest, Noel-danchou."
こんばんは。
Good evening.
「私は現在、海外で生活しています。」
"I am currently living abroad."
「現地の方から好意を寄せられていますが、」
"Someone local has expressed feelings for me, but..."
「私自身は数年後には日本へ帰らなければなりません。」
"...I have to return to Japan in a few years."
「そのため、悲しい思いをさせるよりも、現地でもっと素敵な方と過ごしてもらうほうがいいのではと思ってしまいます。」
"Because of that, rather than making them sad, I feel it might be better for them to spend time with someone more wonderful locally."
「3人の意見をお聞きしたいです。」
"I'd like to hear the three of your opinions."
ちょっとマジメモードですね。
We're in serious mode now.
ああ、すごい。うわあ。
Oh, wow.
これ難しい。
This is hard.
難しいね。気持ちはわかるね。
It's hard. But I understand how they feel.
そっか。
I see.
でもなんか、正直に言ってあげてもいいのかなって思っている。
But I think maybe they should just tell them honestly.
ああ、数年後には帰らなきゃいけないんだよって。
Like, "I have to return to Japan in a few years"?
そう。
Yes.
から、その...やっぱり難しいと思うけど。
So, it might still be difficult, but...
それでも愛してくれるなら、日本に来るか、みたいな。
But if they still love you, maybe they'll come to Japan?
まあ、難しいよね。どこのあれなのかもわからないけど。
Well, it's difficult. We don't know where they are, but...
遠距離になっちゃうしね、難しいね。
It would end up being long-distance, so it's hard.
「ついてこいよって言え」っていうコメントもありますけど、どうでしょう。
There's a comment saying, "Tell them to follow you," what do you think?
あ、そう。積極的な人も、そうね。
Ah, yes. Proactive people might do that.
でも、好意を寄せてくれてる人、本当にこよちゃんとかも言ってたけど、
But for the person who has feelings, like Koyori-chan said,
「数年後には帰らなきゃいけないんだ」っていう話をした上で、
Once you tell them, "I have to go back in a few years,"
「悲しい思いをさせるよりは」とかは、相手側の気持ちだから。
saying "rather than making them sad" is deciding on their feelings for them.
自分のそういう状況を伝えた上で、どうするかは、
So, after sharing your situation, what to do...
相手に委ねてもいいんじゃないかなって思ったりするかな。
...should probably be left up to them, I think.
どう、確かに。あ、同意。
Indeed, I agree.
なんかさ、恋愛とかそういうのって、ファンタジーだと思ってて。
You see, I think romance and stuff is like a fantasy.
だから、なんか、こう理屈じゃないんじゃないかと、夢も持ってて、団長の中で。
So I have this dream inside me that it's not about logic.
だから、お互いのそういう気持ちで、なんかこう、無理、難解を乗り越えていくこともあるかもなんで。
So, because of those feelings for each other, you might overcome difficult obstacles.
ちょっと気持ちを素直に行くのもいいんじゃない、なんか大人になりすぎなくても。
So being honest with your feelings might be good, without being too realistic.
あ、確かに。
Ah, that's true.
する。
I think so.
すごい、いい言葉や、大人になりすぎない。
That's a great phrase. "Not being too realistic."
うん。
Yeah.
どうだろうなって感じでした、団長は。
That's how Noel-danchou feels.
同じ気持ちです。
I feel the same way.
いいと思います。なので、ちょっと向き合ってみてください。
I think it's good. So, please try to face them.
幸あれということで。では、続いていきましょう。
Wishing you happiness. Let's move on to the next one.
えー、こちらですね。
Here it is.
「女子ホロリスです。こんばんは。大学の...」
"I'm a female Hololive listener. Good evening. In university..."
大1の女子ホロリスです。恋愛相談なんですけど...
I'm a first-year college student female Holo-listener. I have a relationship question...
この前、他大学の男性と3回目のデートに行ってきました。
The other day, I went on a third date with a guy from another university.
3回目なので告白とか何かしらしてくれるかなと思ったんですけど、何もありませんでした。
Since it was our third date, I thought he'd confess or something, but nothing happened.
それから私の気持ちも冷めてきてしまって、LINEとかする気にも全く乗れなくて、このままでいいのか悩んでいます。
Since then, my feelings have cooled down, and I don't feel like texting him at all, so I'm worried if it's okay to leave things like this.
私はどうすればいいでしょうか？助けて！
What should I do? Help!
とのこと。可愛い。
She says. How cute.
うーん、3回目のデート。
Hmm, a third date.
3回目、どうなんですかね？
What do you think about the third date?
どうなんだろうなぁ...
I wonder...
3回目のデート、何もありませんでした。
On the third date, nothing happened.
え、これって、デートということは、え、これ付き合ってるってこと？
Wait, does "dating" mean... wait, are they going out?
付き合ってない、ない、ない！
They aren't, they aren't!
ないけど、3回デートして、
They aren't, but they've been on three dates...
3回一緒に出かけたら、もうなんか告白とかそういう感じになるかなみたいな、
and she felt like going out together three times would lead to a confession,
って思ってた... あー...
is what she thought. Ah...
なるほど。冷めちゃったなら、
I see. If her feelings have cooled down...
もうそれが答えなのかなぁって思う。
I think that itself is the answer.
男の子が内気すぎて、本当は女の子のこと好きなんだけど、
Maybe the guy is too shy, and although he really likes her...
なんか告白する勇気がなくて、っていうパターンもあると、
he just doesn't have the courage to confess. There could be such a pattern...
私はそっちのパターンかなって思ってるけど、コメントとかは結構「キープ」とかもあったりして。
I thought it might be that pattern, but chat comments also mention things like "being kept on the hook".
あー、それはちょっと、あれだね。
Ah, that's a bit, you know...
むずいね。むずい。
It's tough. Tough.
けど、冷めちゃったなら、どうなんだろう？なんか、
But if her feelings have cooled down, I wonder? Like...
「3回目なので告白とかしてくれるかな」っていう、
Like, having the expectation of "it's our third date, so will he confess?"...
ちょっと今から厳しいこと言うんですけど、っていう期待をしてるのがちょっと、
I'm going to say something harsh here, but having that kind of expectation...
今後のためにも、そういう価値観じゃない方がいいかもって思った。
might not be the best mindset to have for the future, I think.
と言うと？
What do you mean by that?
なんかその、3回目のデートで告白するっていう決まりは全くなかったりとか、
Well, there's absolutely no rule that a confession has to happen on the third date.
結構、この世の中、告白せずになあなあで付き合った、恋人になったみたいな人たちもいたりするから、
In this world, some people end up going out and becoming a couple naturally without a formal confession.
絶対に起こるイベントではないので、期待してなかったら冷めなかったのかなとか、
Since it's not a guaranteed event, maybe if she didn't expect it, her feelings wouldn't have cooled down.
そういうのを考えてみた方がいいのかなって思った。
I thought it might be good to think about it that way.
確かに。なんか、あれだよね。多分、
True. It's like, you know, probably...
相手が何かやってくれる、男の子がその、
She's waiting for the other person to do something. For the guy to...
プロポーズしてくれたりとか、付き合ってって言ったりとか、
ask her out, or ask her to be his girlfriend.
受け身になってはいるよね、この3回目は。
She is being passive, at least on this third date.
まあ、そうだね。
Well, that's true.
女の子は言われたいっていう願望は確かに、あるよね。
Girls definitely have the desire to be asked out.
わかる。わかる、わかる。
I get it. I understand.
だけど、でもやっぱり人によっては、
But, depending on the person...
なかなか積極的な男の子じゃない子もいると思うし、
some guys aren't proactive at all.
付き合うってなると、そこらへん、
And when it comes to dating, that kind of thing...
もう好きだったなら、自分から動くのも大事だと思うから。
If she liked him, taking the initiative herself is also important.
「どうすればいいでしょうか？助けて」ということなので、
She asks, "What should I do? Help!" so...
本当に「もうこの男の子とはいいかな」ってなったら、連絡取らなくてもいいし、
if she really feels "I'm done with this guy," she doesn't need to contact him.
でも、まだちょっと好きな気持ちがあるんだったら、
But if she still has some feelings left...
行ってみるのもいいと思うんだよね。
I think it's worth taking a shot.
ここで冷めちゃうのは、ちょっともったいないなって思う。
I feel it's a bit of a waste to let things cool down here.
そう、3回目までデートに行ったんだもんね、事実は。
Right, the fact is they went on three dates.
時間を割いてね。
Making time for each other.
お互いの時間を使って会ってたわけなんだから、
Since they were spending their mutual time to meet up...
多分、向こうにも好意があることはあるんだろうね、だって3回目もデート行ったんだもんね。
he probably has feelings for her too, since they went on a third date.
でも、やっぱりちょっと期待しちゃったんだね。多分ね、そうだね。
But she probably just expected a bit too much, I guess.
だから本当に気になってるならね、自分からどんどん行っちゃってもいいんじゃないかな？
So if she's really interested, she could just go for it herself.
そうですね、なんか、
Yeah. I feel like...
一旦この期待してた自分をなくして、
she should temporarily set aside her expectations,
で、告白してくれなかったっていうのも全部なくして、その子が好きなのかどうか、
forget that he didn't confess, and think about whether she actually likes him.
っていうことを考えてみて、で、好きなら4回目行ってみようぜ！
And if she does, let's go for a fourth date!
誘ってみてもいいんじゃない？
Why not ask him out?
でも本当に気持ちが冷めちゃったんだったら、もう逆にね、無理して行くことはないし。
But if her feelings have truly cooled down, she doesn't need to force herself either.
ね、そんな気がします。あとは、これは大人...
Yeah, I feel that way too. Also, this is an adult...
になって、っていう感じですけど
It's like that...
人に期待していいことは一つもないので、これは恋愛...
But there is nothing good that comes from expecting things from other people. Be it romance...
その、恋愛でも恋愛じゃなくても。
whether it is romance or not.
そうね。
Right.
なんかやっぱり、あの、期待ってエゴなんで、って思うと、ちょっと楽になるのかな、生き方が、って思いますね。
I feel like thinking of expectations as just ego makes life a little easier, you know?
なるほどね。
I see.
はい。それでは続いて、えーと、男の子ですね。
Yes. Well then, next is... a guy.
「グイグイと話しかけに来るのはどんな意図や背景を持っているんでしょうか？」という、えー悩み相談でございます。
"What kind of intentions or background do they have when they aggressively come talk to you?" That is the consultation we have here.
えーっと、同じ案件作業してるが直接会話が少ない後輩女性。
"A junior female colleague who works on the same project but has little direct conversation."
職場飲み会開催場所移動前に後輩女性から「今日の飲み会出席ですよね。よく食べるとお聞きしたので、残せても大丈夫ですよね」みたいなジャブの会話が来る。
"Before moving to the venue for the office drinking party, the junior colleague jabbed at him with: 'You're attending today's party, right? I heard you eat a lot, so it's okay if there are leftovers, right?'"
偶然にも座席の、座席が同じ場所。
"By chance, their seats at the table were next to each other."
自分はコミュニケーションは高めと自負しているが、突如迫られると、押し込まれるタイプ。
"Though I pride myself on having decent communication skills, I'm the type who gets overwhelmed when suddenly approached."
何かあるのではと背景を見つつ、さりげない会話で終了。
"Sensing there might be something to it, I looked for background context, and the conversation ended casually."
その後、特に進展なし。今のご時世、何があるか分からないという建前を置くチキン野郎です。年齢は30代前半です、と。
"No further progress since then. He says he's a chicken who uses 'you never know what can happen these days' as a pretext. He is in his early 30s."
ああ。なるほど。
Ah, I see.
ま、こういう行動をとる女の子、ま、もし自分のこの後輩女子だとしたら、
So, if a girl behaves like this, supposing she was your junior colleague,
うん。どうなのかな？みたいな妄想ですね。
yeah, "what is her deal?"... it's that kind of speculation.
妄想？これ、なんか、
Speculation? But in this case, isn't it...
相手が好意を持ってるとか、そういうのじゃなくて、何で、こういう、
not necessarily that she has feelings for him, but rather wondering why she...
多分、どういう、どんな意図や背景を持っているんでしょうかと。
Probably, "what kind of intention or background does she have?" is the question.
要するに、おそらく、あの、「この行動してくるって自分のこと好きなの？」っていうのを、
In short, he probably wants to know: "Does this behavior mean she likes me?"
その、女子ってどうなの？って聞きたいんだと思う。
He wants to ask us, "How do girls view this?"
ああ。なるほど。
Ah, I see.
でも、これ、あれだよね。実際に、何だろう、向こうからのアクションとしては、
But really, as far as actual actions from her go...
あの、「今日飲み会来ますよね。いっぱい飲めますよね」って言われたことだけだよね。
it's only that she said, "You're coming to the drinking party today, right? You can eat a lot, right?"
うん、確かに、今書いてある内容だとそれだけかも。
Yeah, based on what's written here, that might be all.
そう、同じ席になったとかはあったけど。
Right, and then their seats happening to be next to each other.
うーん、そんなに、何もなくても聞くかな、みたいな内容って感じ？
So is it like, "Would she ask that even if there was nothing to it?"
まあ、うーん。なんか、こう、
Well, let's see. It's like...
そういう飲み会に行くっていう、さ、きっかけっていうか、あるから、とりあえず、
with the occasion of going to a drinking party, first of all...
飲み会までちょっとテンション、まあ飲み会ってさ、テンション上がるものか分かんないけど、飲み会でテンション上がって、で、なんか、まあ話しかけた、ぐらいな感じなのかな。
getting hyped up for the party... I don't know if drinking parties really get people hyped up, but maybe she was hyped up for it and decided to strike up a conversation.
っていう感じだよね、なんか、本当に。
That's how it feels, really.
まあそうだね、でも、内容としては、グイグイと話しかけに来るっていうことも別であったのかどうなのか。
That's true, but I wonder if there were other times she aggressively came to talk to him.
あった。確かに回数の問題あるかもね。
Ah, indeed, the frequency might be a factor.
うん。
Yeah.
うーん。なんか、コメラは、なんか「何もないよ、安心しろ」で一致しているみたいなんですけど...
Hmm. It seems the comment section is unanimously saying, "There's nothing to it, chill out."
でも、なんか、もし、すごい、
But, if she really...
「え？そんなに俺にだけ話しかけに来る？」みたいな、なんかみんなに同じように、
comes up to talk only to him, unlike with everyone else...
そうそう、そう、なんか飲み会の人数が増やしたくて、みんなに言ってる可能性もあるから。
Right, right. There's a chance she's telling everyone because she wants to increase the attendance.
その、でも、自分にばっかり色んなこと聞いてくるなって、もし思うのであれば、
But if he feels she is specifically asking him all these things...
あの、なんか、聞いてもいいかな、って思っちゃった。
I think he could just ask her.
何を？「そんなに、なんか俺のこと気にしてくれてんの？」みたいな。
Ask what? Like, "Are you that interested in me?"
ちょっと軽く。そんなグイグイ来てるなら、こっちも軽く、
Just lightly. Since she's being aggressive, he can lightly...
ジャブ打つ。
throw a jab back.
ジャブ。いや、昨今、昨今、怖い！
A jab. But nowadays, nowadays it's scary!
そう、難しいんだよね、その。この方も心配してますしね、ちょっと。
Yeah, it is difficult. And this sender is a bit worried about that too.
そうなんだよね。すごい慎重派な方なんで。
Right. He seems like a very cautious person.
だから、もう本当に、なんだろう、でもグイグイ系だったら、え、なんか、やっぱ昨今ね、結構、あるらしく。
So, really... but if she's the aggressive type, well, nowadays apparently it happens quite a bit.
怖い、これダメそうだな、コンプライアンス。
Scary... This might get flagged by compliance.
こよちゃん男の子でこういう悩める子羊だったらちょっとやばかった。
If Koyo were a boy and a lost sheep worrying like this, it would've been trouble.
なんか、そう、なんかグイグイ、その、まだね、情報も薄いしってことは、そんなに他でグイグイ、エピソードが揃ってないってことだから。
Right. Since the information is still thin, it means there aren't many other episodes of her being aggressive.
一旦、前普通に、何だろう、仕事続けて、会話やってでいい気がするな。
For now, he should just keep working normally and converse normally. I think that's fine.
そうですね。
True.
そう、そう。ただ、そんなに意識し...
Right, right. No need to be so conscious...
意識して、多分、結構色んな人に話しかけるタイプの女性だったんじゃなかろうかという
I think she was probably the type of woman who intentionally talked to many different people...
うん。性格的な感じかも。だな？
Yeah. It might just be her personality. Right?
あれに「二人でご飯行きましょう」とか言われたら、もう一回考えてみただな。そうだね。
If she asked, "Let's go grab a bite, just the two of us," then you could reconsider. Yeah, true.
はい。ということで。
Yes, so there you go.
はい。じゃあちょっとあと2つ読んでもいいですか？もちろん。どうぞ、どうぞ。
Alright. Can I read two more? Of course. Go ahead, go ahead.
女の子と男の子それぞれいこうと思うんですけれども。
I'd like to do one from a girl and one from a boy.
えー、可愛いやつです。「学生の女子大生です！」
Okay, here's a cute one. "I'm a female student!"
あら、大生さん。
Oh, a student.
「今絶賛片思い中なのですが、どうすれば相手に振り向いてもらえますか？」
"I'm in the middle of a massive crush. How can I get him to notice me?"
「モテる行動とかヘアスタイルを教えてほしいです。」
"I'd like to know some attractive behaviors or hairstyles."
「ちなみにユニバのアトラクション、二人で乗ったことあります。幸せ！」
"By the way, we've ridden a USJ attraction together. I'm so happy!"
可愛い！可愛い！
So cute! So cute!
はい、優勝。優勝！
She wins. She totally wins!
可愛い。超可愛いんです。可愛いね。
How cute. She's so cute. It's adorable, isn't it?
どうですか？モテる行動とかヘアスタイル教えてほしいって。
What do you think? She wants to know popular actions and hairstyles.
え、でもさ、その好きな男の子がさ、どんなスタイルが好きなのかにもよるくない？
But wouldn't that depend on what style the boy she likes prefers?
そうなんだよね。そう、確かにね。
That's true. Yeah, definitely.
この子に似合うとかも大事だったりするしな。
It's also important what suits her.
まあでも本当に一つだけ言えるのは、もうすでに可愛い。恋している乙女。可愛いよ。
But really, the one thing I can say is she's already cute. A girl in love is adorable.
可愛い。可愛い。
So cute. So cute.
もういっぱい、いっぱい笑ってね。笑う女の子が一番最高やから。
Just smile and laugh a lot. A girl who smiles is the absolute best.
確かに！愛嬌だよ、愛嬌。愛嬌。
Exactly! Charm, it's all about charm. Charm.
男は度胸、女は愛嬌。
Courage for men, charm for women.
昔から言うよね。
People have said that for ages.
いや、でも大事だと思うよ。笑顔よく、「俺の前だとすごい人一倍この子笑ってくれるな」とかさ。
But I do think it's important to smile. To make him think, "She smiles so much more when she's with me."
絶対キュンとくるポイントでしょ。そうだね、本当に。
That's definitely a heart-fluttering point. Yeah, absolutely.
なんかこの、幸せって思っているやつを、伝わるぐらいニコニコしまくり、話しかけたりとかしてもいいのかなって。
I think it's good to smile so much that her happiness gets transmitted, and just talk to him.
そうだね。そうだね、思っちゃいます。
Yeah. I think so too.
はい。大事、大事。いや、本当にそうだ。
Yes. Important, important. Yeah, really.
自信持って、すでに可愛いので。
Have confidence, because you're already cute.
あとはあれかな。もしヘアスタイルとか変えたいなら、「好きな女の子の髪型とかあるの？」って聞いて、
Also, if you want to change your hairstyle, you could ask him, "What kind of girls' hairstyles do you like?"
次の日それをやってくる、っていう、あざとテク。
And then do that the very next day. A sly technique.
あ、めっちゃ意識してるじゃん！俺のこと！
"Ah, she's totally conscious of me!"
そういうのどう思う？
How do you feel about that?
え、可愛くない？可愛い。
Wait, isn't that cute? It's cute.
可愛いよね。可愛い。
It's cute, right? Cute.
そういうのやってみちゃってもいいかもしれない。
You could try doing something like that.
って、思います。いいと思います。
That's what I think. I think that's good.
それをやってなんか変な感じになったらどうしようって今ちょっとソワソワしてるんですけど。
I'm getting a bit anxious wondering, "What if I try it and it feels awkward?"
大丈夫、大丈夫。責任負えないな。
You'll be fine, you'll be fine. I can't take responsibility!
まあね、相手の男の子がどういう感じなのか分からないからね。
Well, yeah, because we don't know what the guy is like.
でも可愛いでしょう。可愛い。
But it's bound to be cute. Cute.
それでは、ラストは男子からのいこうかなと思いますけれども。
Now, let's go to the last letter, which is from a guy.
「大人の女性ならではの魅力をお持ちの、すのずの＆ノエたんさんに質問です」
"I have a question for Sunozuno & Noe-tan, who possess the unique charm of adult women."
「私はいつか、素敵な「お姉さんタイプ」の女性とお付き合いをして、お互いに支え合えるような関係を築きたいと思っています。」
"I hope to someday date a wonderful 'big sister type' woman and build a relationship where we can support each other."
「そこで質問なのですが、お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣や、」
"So, my question is: what is the secret to dating a big sister type,"
「「こういう男性だといいな」と思うポイントなどはありますでしょうか？ぜひお二人の意見、3人ですね、の意見やアドバイスを聞かせていただけると嬉しいです」
"or what kind of qualities make you think, 'This guy is great'? I'd love to hear advice or opinions from the two—or rather, three of you."
あらあら。大人女性、あらあら。
My, my. An adult woman, my, my.
あらあら。大人のお姉さんに憧れている。
My, my. Longing for an adult big sister.
「お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣」
"The secret to dating a big sister type woman..."
お姉さんもね、色んなタイプがいるからね。
There are many different types of big sisters.
ノエたんタイプのお姉さん、優しい、ほんわかしたお姉さんとお付き合いするには...
To date a Noe-tan type big sister, a kind and gentle big sister...
うん
Yeah.
ありがとう
Thank you.
えー、でも、そうだなぁ、なんか
Well, but... let's see, like...
普通に変にさ、背伸びしなくていいと
I think you don't need to try too hard to act mature...
思っていい感じの、一貫してるね、うん。
...which is a consistent answer, yeah.
そう、なんか本当に、こう真面目に、そう、生きて
Yeah, like, really living seriously...
なんか精一杯、精一杯で頑張ってるところとかを
...and doing your absolute, absolute best...
なんか結構、あれなんじゃないかな？
...is probably the key, don't you think?
そう、せ... なんか
Yeah, so... wait,
感じがちょっと難しい。自分がさ、お姉さん、お姉さんタイプでいいのかって思いながら。
this is a bit hard. I was wondering if I should even count as the "older sister" type.
お姉さんだよ、お姉さん。うん。
You are an older sister, definitely! Yeah.
甘やかしてくれそう、っていうのが、なんかお姉さん感。そうだね。うん。
You feel like someone who would spoil us, which gives off an older sister vibe. / Yeah, indeed.
なんか本当に、まじ、なんだろう。精一杯、精一杯頑張ってる姿とかが、
Like, really, how should I say it? Seeing someone do their absolute best...
まぁ、それはさ、なんかお姉さんとか関係なく、人として、なんか素晴らしいと思うからさ。
Well, putting aside being an "older sister" or not, as a person, that's wonderful.
だから、そ、そんな感じかな？
So, I think it's something like that.
なんか、特にこういうね、こういうところがいい、みたいなさ、ピンポイントで言えなくて申し訳ないけど、
I'm sorry I can't give a pinpoint answer like, "I specifically like this trait," but...
一生懸命、なんか生きてる人は、すごい魅力的だな、って思う。
...I find people who are living their life to the fullest extremely attractive.
で、そういう人は甘やかしたいな、って思う。
And I feel like I'd want to spoil someone like that.
うわー！今日、お仕事頑張る！
Wow! I'm going to work so hard at my job today!
褒めて、褒めて！
Praise me! Praise me!
どういうことですかね？ってやっていいってことですよね？
Is that how it works? So I can do that to you, right?
うん。え、でもちょっと、思うんですけど、その、
Yeah. / But I was thinking,
お姉さんに好かれるって、なんか、そのバブみとかさ、あの、なんか甘えるタイプがやっぱりお姉さんに好かれるのかな、みたいな、こう、二次元の、というか、イメージ。
to be liked by an older sister, isn't there an anime-like image of someone with "baby-ishness" who likes to be pampered?
あー、があるじゃないですか。
Ah, right, that kind of image exists.
だからといって、その、バブバブーって生きる、ん、ではな、ないよな、って思うんですけど、どうでしょうか？
But that doesn't mean you should actually live your life going "babu, babu," right? What do you think?
いや、でも、バブバブは...
Well, but going "babu babu"...
バブバブだめですか？
Is going "babu babu" no good?
いや、なんかそれもそれで、可愛くてあり。
No, in its own way, that's also cute and totally fine!
あ、そうなんだ！ちょっと包容力がある、あり。いや、あり、ありだな。
Oh, really? So you have the tolerance for it. / Yeah, it's totally fine.
だから本当に難しい。なんか、そういうことを言って、これ戦略だと思うと、その、
That's why it's so difficult. If we're talking strategy,
まる主さんが、どういうタイプ？こういうのってさ、あの、よし悪しとかが、よしあしじゃなくて、その、タイプってあるじゃん。
it depends on what type you are. It's not about being good or bad, but more about your style.
その自分は、例えば背が高いから、そういう、なんか、カッコいい系で、なんかちょっとスタイリングしてます、とか。
Like, "Since I'm tall, I try to style myself in a cool way,"
逆に、いや自分結構、幼い、童顔って言われるから、幼い感じで、とか、
or "Since people say I have a baby face, I'll go for a youthful look."
なんかそういう、なんか、戦略？やっぱり自分に合った感じとかも、大事かな、あと性格とかも。だから...
I think that kind of strategy—finding what suits you, including your personality—is important. So...
なんだろうな。うーん、なんかどのタイプでも、なんか普通にお姉さんに好かれそう、な気がする。精一杯に背伸びしてるタイプも、バブバブなタイプも。
Let's see... I feel like any type would normally be liked by an older sister, whether they're trying hard to look mature or acting like a baby.
でも、逆に、なんか本当にNGなようなことをしなければ、なんかいいな、って。
On the flip side, as long as you don't do things that are absolute "no-gos," it should be fine.
清潔感、清潔感！
Cleanliness! Cleanliness is key!
もうこれはあれだね。お姉さんとかお姉さんじゃないとか、もう別で、
At this point, it has nothing to do with being an older sister or not...
関係なく、人に好かれるということ、みたいな感じですかね。
...it's just about being liked by people in general.
難しい。本当に、本当なんかちょっと、いや、むずいね。うん、うん。こちらは難しいんだけど。
It's difficult. Really, it's quite tough. Yeah, this is a hard question.
まぁ、人にもよるから、みたいなところはあるよね。ラミたん、お姉さんとして、としたら、どう？
Well, it also depends on the person. Lamy, what if you were the older sister?
ラミ、お姉さん属性ある？
Does Lamy even have "older sister" traits?
うーん、あんまりない。ある、ある！あるよ、あるよ。
Hmm, not really... / You do, you do! You definitely do.
でも、みんなお姉さんっぽーいって言ってるから、この人は。
But everyone in chat is saying she seems like an older sister.
おー、そうんだ。ラミにお姉さん属性。
Oh, really? Lamy has older sister traits...
いやー、でも、やっぱお姉さんも関係ないかもな。人として、になっちゃうな、なんか。うん、うん。
Well, but maybe "older sister" doesn't even matter. I think it just comes down to them as a person.
ラミは、やっぱ尊敬できる人が魅力的に見えるから、
For me, I find people I can respect to be attractive...
お仕事頑張ってるとか、なんか好きなことを、なんかね、追っかけてるとか、なんかそういうの、ところに魅力を感じるかな。
...so I find charm in things like working hard at their job, or chasing after what they love.
から、やっぱりあれかね。その、誠実に生きる。お姉さんとかは1回置いておいて。
So, I guess it's about living sincerely, putting "older sister" aside for a moment.
え、こよりは、こよりはどうなの？私も、お姉さんなのかな、っていう感じでは、あるんだけど、
What about Koyori? Well, I wonder if I'm the older sister type as well, but...
でも、なんかやっぱり支え合えるような関係を築きたい、っていう風に言ってるから、それを大事にしていくことなのかな、と思いますね。
...since they mentioned wanting to build a supportive relationship, I think focusing on that is what's important.
で、その、でも、なんかお姉さんタイプの女性とって、
And regarding what "an older sister type of woman" is...
だから、うん。決めつけなくていいのかなと思っていて。
So, yeah. I think you don't need to force yourself to define it.
うん、うん。
Yeah, indeed.
なんか、好きになった人がお姉さんだったなら、お姉さんだし。
Like, if the person you fall in love with happens to be an older sister type, then they're an older sister.
もしかしたら、全然お姉さんじゃない人を好きになるかもしれないから、この人自身も。
Or you might end up falling for someone who isn't an older sister type at all, even for this person themselves.
なんか、その時に「あ、お姉さんじゃないな」ってならないで、
So when that happens, instead of thinking, "Ah, they're not an older sister..."
好きになったなら、その好きになった人と幸せになってほしいなって思います。
...if you fall in love, I hope you can be happy with the person you love.
そうね。うん。
That's true. Yeah.
から、もう幸せ、幸あれ。幸あれ。幸あれですね。
So, I wish you happiness. May you be blessed. May you be blessed indeed.
うん。で、なんかちょっとね、一個、今の話の流れでですね、ちょっと悩んでた人がいるんで、
Yeah. And actually, following this topic... someone else was worrying about something,
一個だけ、ちょっと、補足でいくんですけども。
...so I'd like to bring up just one more additional thing here.
ぜひぜひ！ほう、ほう、ほう。
Please do! I see, I see.
「質問です。女性から見て恋愛や結婚に前をのめりにならず、自分のやりたいことに挑戦や目標に向けての行動を最優先して取り組んでいる男性ってどう思いますか？」っていうのがあったんですよ。
"Here is a question. What do you think of men who don't rush into romance or marriage, but prioritize pursuing their own goals and challenges?" That was the question.
うわー！え、いいじゃん！え、ええやん！
Wow! Huh, that's great! Why, that's totally fine!
これはなに？えっと、付き合ってる彼女がいてってこと？
What does this mean? Like, he already has a girlfriend?
多分、そういうことではなく、自分自身が恋愛とか結婚とか多分なにも興味なく、
No, probably not. More like he himself has no interest in romance or marriage...
うん、仕事に一生懸命なんだと思うの。今でもさ、「仕事に一生懸命な人って素敵」みたいな話があったやん？「どう思いますか？」っていうのは。
...and is just focused on his work. We were just talking about how hardworking people are wonderful, right? So he's asking, "What do you think of that?"
おおー。
Oh...
恋愛対象になるかな、みたいな話でもちょっと考えてみるといいのかな。
I wonder if he's asking if such a person can be seen as a romantic interest.
いや、もう、え、もう良さしかなくて、今ちょっと、あれなんですけど。
Well, honestly, I only see good things in that. But actually...
なん、なんだろうな。なんか、団長的にこう、個人的に思うのが、
How should I put it? Personally, speaking as Danchou...
めちゃめちゃやっぱ、そう尊敬できるからさ、すごいなって思う反面、
...I'd really respect someone like that and think they're amazing, but on the other hand...
ただ、隙がないかな、とも思う。ああ、確かに、確かに。
...I might feel like they have no openings. Ah, true, true.
もしかしたら、近寄り難い、みたいな。そういうところはちょっとある、なんか。
Like, maybe they seem a bit unapproachable. I feel like there's a bit of that.
多分、恋愛とかってさ、お互いのその、歩み寄りだったり、その、歩幅とかがちょっと違いすぎると破綻しちゃうと思うから、
Probably, because in romance, if you are too far apart in terms of pacing and compromises, it won't work out.
多分、このマロ主さんはすごい良いなって団長は思ったのって、きっと団長もね、今こうやってホロライブでさ、活動すごい頑張っててさ、
So, Danchou thought this marshmallow sender was great because Danchou herself is working hard here in Hololive right now...
お仕事に、あ、こよちゃんが「わー」ってなってるけど、
...and is fully focused on work—ah, Koyo-chan is going "Wow!" in reaction...
これ、仕事にこう、一筋みたいなところがあるから、なんか、同志だ、みたいな気持ちで思ったんだけど。ただ、
...since there's a shared focus on being dedicated to work, I felt a sense of camaraderie. But...
やっぱ、その恋愛とか結婚とかしたい子からすると、
...from the perspective of someone who actually wants romance or marriage...
ちょっと、あれかも。隙がなくて近寄り難いっていうのはあるかもな、って思った。
...it might be a bit tough. They might feel there are no openings and find him unapproachable.
素晴らしい！素晴らしい！拍手が出てきた。
Wonderful! Wonderful! That deserves applause.
もう、こよの顔ずっとニコニコやったよ。
Koyo, you've had a grin on your face this whole time!
ニコニコというか、なんか、これね、すごい素敵じゃん。お二人のさっき話してた内容も含めて、すてきやん！ってなるなって思ったの。
Well, it's not just a grin. It's just so wonderful. Including everything you two were just talking about, I was just thinking, "That's so great!"
でも、こよりは一個、この子に伝えたいなって思ったことがあって。それはすごく素敵なことだし、とっても人間として素敵なんだけど、
But there's one thing Koyori wanted to tell this person. While it is wonderful and makes you a great person...
その生活をずっと続けていると、何も起きないぞ。気をつけろって。
...if you keep living like that, nothing will ever happen. So watch out!
ていう、なんか言うだけは言ってあげたいなって思ったのね。
That's the one thing I really wanted to tell them.
で、それを言って締めようかな、ぐらいに思って今これを取り上げたんですけど、
I actually picked this message intending to wrap things up with that warning...
その理由が、もうノエたんの口から全部出たから、すごい拍手でした。
...but then Noe-tan explained all the reasons perfectly, so I just had to applaud!
ああ、なるほどね。解決策が出たと思って。
Ah, I see. I felt like the solution had been presented.
なんか、その生活をしつつも、ちょっと隙を、隙というもの、やっぱり結婚とか恋愛とかしたいなと思ったら、隙が必要なんですかね、多分ね。
Like, while keeping up that lifestyle, if you do want marriage or romance, you need to show some "openings," right? Probably.
隙って何ですかね？
But what exactly is an "opening"?
でも、隙ってやっぱりあれ、なんかさ、多分、忙しそうにしてる、なんか、
Well, "openings" are probably... like, if you always look busy...
どう、やっぱり忙しいんだな、みたいな、なんか、
...people will think, "Oh, they must be really busy," and...
多分、遊ぶ時間もないんだろうな、とかさ。そういうの思われちゃいそうだから、普通になんか趣味も楽しんでますよ、みたいな。
...they'll assume you don't even have time to hang out. So showing that you also enjoy your hobbies...
仕事だけじゃなくて。
...and not just work.
で、趣味を楽しんでるってことは、「あ、時間もちょっと余裕があって」って。
If you're enjoying hobbies, they'll think, "Ah, they have some free time too."
そういうところかな。なんか、まあね。大々的にその、恋愛とか、ちょっと興味あります、とかアピールできればいいけど、それってやりすぎるとちょっと逆にね、あれになっちゃうから、本当にそういう隙？
Maybe something like that. Well, it would be great if you could openly show interest in romance, but trying too hard might have the opposite effect, so just those kinds of "openings."
趣味とか、余裕とかかな、って思う。
Like hobbies or showing you have some free time.
そこに隙を感じる、ということですね。こよりが今、学んでる、学んでる。
So that's where people find "openings." Koyori is taking notes right now!
なるほど、好きのこだわりじゃないからね。
I see, because it's not a strict preference.
（笑）
[Laughter]
ちょっとこよりが答えられない質問だからさ、これ。
Since it's a question Koyori can't really answer...
だから、その、ありがたいなと思って、答えてもらえて。
I was really grateful that you two answered it.
ラミたんが女の子として「好き」と感じるのは他に何かあったりする？
Lamy-tan, what else makes you feel like you "like" someone as a girl?
えー、でも、やっぱり趣味は大きいんじゃない？
Hmm, but hobbies are a big factor, aren't they?
うん、そう、そうだね。
Yeah, that's true.
でもさ、この方さ、「自分のやりたいことに挑戦してる」って書いてあるからさ。
But this person wrote that they are "taking on challenges they want to do."
まあお仕事だけではなくて、自分のやりたいこともできてるってことでしょ？
That means they are doing what they want, not just working, right?
うん、多分、多分。
Yeah, probably.
すごくいいと思うけどね。めちゃくちゃ素敵だと思いますよ。
I think that's really great. I think it's wonderful.
素晴らしい。
That's splendid.
じゃあさ、この人多分まだ好きな人とかいるわけじゃないと思うんだけど、
Well, I don't think this person has someone they like yet...
趣味を満喫してそうな雰囲気を出すのに、ちょっとストラップを付けてみるとか。
But to show they are enjoying their hobby, maybe they could wear a strap...
例えば、我々のようなちいかわ好きとかだったら、ちいかわのキーホルダーをつけてたりすると、
For example, if they like Chiikawa like we do, wearing a Chiikawa keychain...
「あ、ちいかわ好きで推し活してたりするのかな？」みたいなところから、会話が生まれたりとかね。
might make people think, "Oh, do they do fan activities?" and start a conversation.
ある。そういうのどうですかね？何にも付けてないとかだったら。
True. How about doing something like that if you have nothing on?
なんか、その仕事とか普段のそういうTPOにもよるけど、
Well, it depends on their job and the time, place, and occasion...
でもなんか、団長めっちゃいいなって思った。
But I thought that's a really great idea.
なんか、その、それも「好き」ではあるかなって。
I feel like that is also a sign of "liking" something.
良いと思う。
I think it's good.
なんかさっきのね、マシュマロの人もいたけどさ。「ちいかわ一人で男性が見たいけど...」って言ってたけど、
Like that marshmallow person from earlier who said, "I want to see Chiikawa alone but as a guy..."
いや、普通にそれって、可愛いポイントだと団長思うから。
I think that's actually a cute point.
なんかに、そういうマスコットとか、ものにもよるのかも。仕事場につけていいか。
So, having a mascot like that... well, it depends on whether it's okay for the workplace.
でもなんかいいなって思う。
But I think it's nice.
思います。
I agree.
話しかけるきっかけになりそうですね。
It seems like a good conversation starter.
そういう隙を作りつつ、お仕事がんばる君は素敵だよ、ということでね。
Showing that kind of vulnerability while working hard is wonderful.
はーい。
Yes.
で、えー、締めたいと思います。すいません、ちょっと色々拾いたいのが色々あって、
And with that, I'd like to wrap up. Sorry, there were so many things I wanted to talk about...
時間ちょっと長くなっちゃったんですけれど、
so it took a bit longer than planned.
今日はどうでしたか？ノエたん。
How was today, Noe-tan?
いやー、もう、出れてよかった！楽しかった！
Well, I'm just so glad I could join! It was so much fun!
このガチトークだから本当にガチな話色々、聞けたりできたりして、
Since this is "Gachi Talk," we really talked about serious stuff.
あとマシュマロでもね、こういう悩んでる子がこんなにたくさんいるんだなと思って。
Also, through the marshmallows, I realized so many people are worried about these things.
あ、一点だけ！団長さ、脱毛のデメリット、言うの忘れてた。
Oh, just one thing! I forgot to mention the downside of hair removal.
ちょっとこれだけ伝えたい。全身脱毛の話なんだけど、
I just have to share this. It's about full-body hair removal.
あのね、毛がないからさ、ボディソープが泡立たなくなった。
You see, since there's no hair, the body soap doesn't lather anymore.
え？！そんなことある？
What?! Is that even possible?
そんなことある？ってあるんだよ！団長、全身脱毛したことあるんだけど、
Is that even possible? Yes, it is! I've done full-body hair removal before.
でも、昔はさ、学生の時とかはさ、
But in the past, like when I was a student...
全然、毛があったからさ、泡立ってたのよ、体。だから、わざわざこう、
I had hair, so my body would lather. So I didn't need to...
ゴシゴシする、なんていうの？ボディソープを泡立てるバスたおるみたいのあるじゃん。
scrub with... what do you call it? Those foaming bath towels.
あ、あるある。
Oh, right, those.
ああいうのを使わなくてよかったんだけど、毛がなくなったら、
I didn't need to use those. But once the hair was gone...
そう、つるつるで。
Yes, it's so smooth.
泡立てなきゃいけなくなった。
I had to lather it myself.
毛で泡立ててたの？！
You were lathering with your hair?!
そんなわけ...
No way...
毛を泡立て器代わりに？
Using hair as a latherer?
いや、泡立て、もしかしたらね、
Well, maybe...
どれだけ生えてたの？
How hairy were you?
ボディソープの問題じゃないの？
Isn't that just a body soap issue?
色々あるかもしれないけど、もしかしたらね、この脱毛考えてる人の中で、
There might be various reasons, but for those considering hair removal...
「自分も毛で泡立ててたわ」みたいな人がいたら、そこはデメリットになるから、気をつけた方がいいかなっていう。
who also "lathered with hair," this could be a downside, so watch out.
真剣な話かなと思ったら、なんかえーって。
I thought it was a serious topic, but...
そんなことあるんだ。なるほど。
I see, that can happen.
でも、あの、泡々になる、あのもふもふってなってるやつ使ってるんだけど、こより。
But, you know, I use that fluffy, net-like thing to make bubbles.
泡立てができるやつ。
The one that foams up.
そう、網網になって、網網がフワフワフワって集まってるやつ。
Yeah, the net one that is all gathered up and fluffy.
あるある！
I know that one!
あれ使えば、最初からブワーって泡立って、そのまま滑らせればOK。
If you use that, it foams up instantly, and you can just slide it over.
あれ、あれすごい、あれ革命よね。
That is amazing. That is a revolution.
革命。
A revolution.
だから、全身脱毛する人はそれを買って...
So, people doing full-body hair removal should buy that...
そうそう、泡立てネットがないと
Right. Without a foaming net...
泡立たない、泡立たない。
...it won't lather up. It won't.
泡立って、まあそういうものなのかな？
It lathers... I guess that's how it is?
まあ、そういう人もいるってことですね。
Well, I guess there are people like that.
ちょっと個人差はあると思いますけど。
I think there are individual differences.
泡立てネットおすすめなんで、ぜひ男子諸君も使っていただければ...
I highly recommend foaming nets, so boys, please use them...
使ってください。/ ...と思います。
Please use them. / ...I think.
でもどうなんだろうね。
But I wonder...
もちろん、すね毛とかさ、そういうのは私は生えてなかったけど、男の人ってすね毛とか
Of course, like, leg hair and stuff... I didn't have any, but men have leg hair...
腕毛とか濃い人いるじゃん。
...and some have thick arm hair, right?
逆にね、毛がある人が使うと、毛がすごい絡まっちゃうかもしれないから。
On the contrary, if someone with hair uses it, their hair might get really tangled.
あ、泡立てネットにか？
Ah, in the foaming net?
うん。泡立てネット、だから、そっ、/ 毛が絡まることあるの？！
Yeah. The foaming net. So... / Can hair really get tangled?!
えっ、剛毛だと？
Wait, if they're hairy?
そう、剛毛だと、いっぱい生えてると、そう...
Yeah, if they're really hairy and have a lot of it...
想像したんだけど、こうやって、なんかめっちゃつきそうだから、
I just imagined it, like, it seems like it would get caught a lot...
あれ、その人は...
So that person...
あの、これからはね、あの、毛で...
...from now on, they can just use their hair...
毛で泡立てて... / 「ねえよ！」って言われてるよ、チャットに。
...lather up with their hair... / They're saying "No way!" in the chat.
ない？嘘、ないか。わかんない、想像で話しちゃった。
Not possible? Really? Guess not. I don't know, I was just imagining it.
私、泡立てネットのね、あの、小さな穴の一つ一つに毛がはい、入っちゃうから、絡まっちゃうのかなーって。
I thought, because the hair would go into each of the tiny holes of the foaming net, that's why it gets tangled.
ちょっと、ボーボーぐらいの毛だったなら、一回、ちょっと、やめてみて、お試しでね、使ってみるといいかもしれないですね。
If your hair is super bushy, you might want to stop once, and maybe just try it out to see.
そうですね。/ なるほど。
Right. / I see.
なるほどなるほど。はい、お気遣いありがとうございます。
I see, I see. Yes, thank you for your concern.
楽しんでもらえてよかったです。ありがとうございます。
I'm glad you enjoyed it. Thank you so much.
じゃあ、らみちゃんは今日どうでしたか？
So, Lamy-chan, how was it for you today?
え、私は二人の体を隅々まで洗えるということが確定したので、
Well, now that it's confirmed that I can wash every nook and cranny of your bodies,
確定？！
Confirmed?!
確定したので、あの、洗う順番とかね、何を使ったらいいのかと、いうのを聞いておこうと思います。
Since it's confirmed, I'm going to ask about the order of washing, and what I should use.
ありがとうございます、待って、それどうしよう、そう、あ、はい、
Thank you. Wait, what should we do about that? Yes...
え、じゃあこよりは？
What about Koyori?
はい、えっと、こよりはちょっと今のらみちゃんの言動で、本当に洗われることがあるのだろうかと、ちょっと男子小学生の気分になっているんですけども、
Yes! Well, Koyori is wondering if she's really going to get washed after what Lamy-chan just said. I feel a bit like an elementary school boy,
本当かもって、ちょっと今緊張してしまっているんですけども、はい。
thinking "Is this really happening?" and feeling a bit nervous now.
え、やっぱこのゲストがいるとまたね、らみこよとまた別の価値観だったりとか、こう出てこない発想とかだったりが出てきて、
But, you know, having a guest here brings different values and ideas that Lamy-Koyo wouldn't usually think of,
ノエルたんが、とにかく優しいし、
and Noel-tan is just so kind,
なんか、包容力？ねえ、結局何でも受け止めてくれそうだなーっていうので、なんか、より好きになってしまいました。
and she has this embracing presence. It feels like she'd accept anything, which made me like her even more.
えー、嬉しい！
Aw, I'm so happy!
団長も本当にさ、このガチトーク出たかったから、今回ゲストに、そう、出れて嬉しいんだけど、
I really wanted to be on Gachi Talk, so I'm so happy to be here as a guest,
確かにこよちゃんがね、冒頭で言ってた、結構人を選んでしまうのではないか、みたいな言ってたけど、
but it's true, just like Koyo-chan said at the beginning, that it might not be for everyone,
でも団長はね本当に、今後もこのガチトーク、
but I really hope this Gachi Talk continues in the future,
続いていって、なんか、まあ、このね、ラインがオッケーなホロメンとかも出て、
and that other Holomembers who are fine with this line of talk will appear,
価値観とか、いろいろ聞けたらなー、嬉しいなと思っておりますので。/ 優しいな、ありがとう。
so we can hear various perspectives. That would make me very happy. / You're so kind, thank you.
あ、ちなみに、もういつでもね、暇なんで、もし、よかったら、いつでも借り出して、
Oh, by the way, I'm free anytime, so if you'd like, you can call on me anytime,
永遠にゲストとか、やりますので。/ 無限、無限ゲストだ！
and I'll be a guest forever. / Infinite, infinite guest!
スノヌエルになる可能性がありますね、またね。
It might become "Sunonuel" eventually. Please do.
嬉しい、またね、やっぱり女子一人増えると、いろんな価値観があるんだなーって、今日もすごく楽しかったです。ありがとうございました。
I'm so glad. Having one more girl really shows how many different values there are, and it was so much fun today. Thank you very much!
またぜひノエルたんも遊びに来てください。/ はい、遊びに来てください。
Please come visit us again, Noel-tan. / Yes, please invite me.
感想は『#すのすの女子トーク』で、ぜひハッシュタグで呟いてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
If you have any thoughts, please tweet them with the hashtag #すのすの女子トーク. We'd appreciate it!
ということで、夜遅くまでありがとうございました。それでは、おつガチトークでいきますか。
With that, thank you for staying with us so late. Shall we end with "Otsu Gachi Talk"?
はい。/ 閉めます。せーの、
Yes. / Let's close it out. Ready, set...
おつガチトーク！
Otsu Gachi Talk!
おやすみなさい！
Good night!
また会いに来てね。
Come see me again!